<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><teiHeader><fileDesc><titleStmt><title>Description of Maḥzor minhag Ashkenaz le-Shavuʻot ule-Sukot(מחזור מנהג אשכנז לשבועות ולסוכות ‬)</title><respStmt><resp>cataloger</resp><persName>Ilana Tahan</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>submitter</resp><persName>Agata Paluch</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>converted to OPenn TEI format</resp><orgName>Schoenberg Institute for Manuscript Studies</orgName></respStmt><funder>The Polonsky Foundation</funder></titleStmt><publicationStmt><publisher>The British Library</publisher><availability><licence target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">This metadata, accompanying images, and the content of
                                        London, British Library, Oriental Manuscripts Add MS 22413: Maḥzor minhag Ashkenaz le-Shavuʻot ule-Sukot are free of known
                                        copyright restrictions and in the public domain. See the
                                        Creative Commons Zero 1.0 Universal page for usage details,
                                        https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/.</licence><licence target="https://www.bl.uk/help/ethical-terms-of-use">
                                        The [British] Library respects the intellectual property
                                        rights, including moral rights, of rights holders and makes
                                        all reasonable effort to contact and consult rights owners,
                                        including, where appropriate, communities directly, or via
                                        local community organisations. Given the importance of the
                                        historical record, and the fact that that some of our
                                        digitised collections include materials that are sensitive
                                        to particular communities and groups, we ask that any use of
                                        the digitised collections is undertaken with the appropriate
                                        care. Irrespective of its copyright status, items and/or
                                        collections should not be altered or used in ways that might
                                        be derogatory to the originating individuals or communities.
                                        (Please follow the link for the complete text of the BL
                                        Ethical Terms of Use)</licence></availability></publicationStmt><notesStmt><note>Coats of arms of Bavaria and Austria at a depiction of two knights fighting (volume 1, folio 103v). The scene may refer to a battle between King Frederick the Fair of Austria and his rival king, King Louis IV the Bavarian, at Mühldorf in 1322. This data is one of the criteria on which the manuscript was dated, see 130, and  294. 
								Ya῾aḳov Daniyel bar Avraham Ulmo: inscribed with his name (folio 1r). An obituary entry of 1572 (folio 167v). </note><note type="relatedResource">
								Manuscript description based on Margoliouth, G.: Catalogue of the Hebrew and Samaritan Manuscripts in the British Museum, London 1965.
							</note></notesStmt><sourceDesc><msDesc><msIdentifier><country>United Kingdom</country><settlement>London</settlement><institution>British Library</institution><repository>Oriental Manuscripts</repository><collection>Hebrew Manuscripts Digitisation
                                            Project</collection><idno type="call-number">Add MS 22413</idno><altIdentifier type="resource"><idno>http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_22413</idno></altIdentifier><altIdentifier type="bl_website"><idno>https://www.bl.uk/hebrew-manuscripts</idno></altIdentifier></msIdentifier><msContents><summary>Festival prayer book for Shavuʻot (Feast of Weeks) and Sukot (Feast of the Tabernacles), German rite, including biblical readings. The Book of Ruth and the Book of Ecclesiastes with Joseph Ḳara's commentary. Aka the 'Tripartite Maḥzor'.</summary><textLang mainLang="he"/><msItem n="1r"><locus from="1r" to="167v">1r-167v</locus><title>Maḥzor minhag Ashkenaz le-Shavuʻot ule-Sukot מחזור מנהג אשכנז לשבועות ולסוכות ‬</title></msItem><msItem n="1r"><locus from="1r" to="83v">1r-83v</locus><title>Services for Shavuʻot </title></msItem><msItem n="83v"><locus from="83v" to="167v">83v-167v</locus><title>Services for Sukot </title></msItem></msContents><physDesc><objectDesc><supportDesc material="parchment"><support><p>Parchment</p></support><extent>167 folios 
									
								</extent><collation><p>
									21 quires: i8, ii8, iii8, iv8, v8, vi8, vii8, viii8, ix12, x6, xi8-1, xii8, xiii8, xiv8, xv8, xvi8, xvii8, xviii8, xix8, xx8, xxi6. 
									No catchwords. 
								</p></collation></supportDesc><layoutDesc><layout><p>Columns: 2 3;
                                                  ruled lines: 26;
                                                  written lines: 26; Uniform layout. Visible ruling with hard-point. Text written in either two or three columns, commentary presented in carmina figurata. Large square initial words. 26 lines to a page of square writing; the semi-cursive commentary arranged variously, often in geometrical figures.</p></layout></layoutDesc></objectDesc><scriptDesc><scriptNote>Ashkenazi square and semi-cursive script, punctuated, of the early 14th century. Ḥayim, inscribed with his name on 80v and 167v; the word חיים is decorated. </scriptNote></scriptDesc><decoDesc><decoNote type="other">12 medallions of the zodiac signs in colours.
							</decoNote><decoNote type="initial"><locus>3r</locus>
								Historiated initial-word panels in colours and gold.</decoNote><decoNote type="initial"><locus>49r</locus>
								Historiated initial-word panels in colours and gold.</decoNote><decoNote type="initial"><locus>71r</locus>
								Historiated initial-word panels in colours and gold.</decoNote><decoNote type="initial"><locus>85r</locus>
								Historiated initial-word panels in colours and gold.</decoNote><decoNote type="initial"><locus>148r</locus>
								Historiated initial-word panels in colours and gold.</decoNote><decoNote type="initial"><locus>98r</locus>Inhabited initial-word panels in colours and gold.
							</decoNote><decoNote type="initial"><locus>106r</locus>Inhabited initial-word panels in colours and gold.
							</decoNote><decoNote type="initial"><locus>131r</locus>Inhabited initial-word panels in colours and gold.
							</decoNote><decoNote type="paratext">Commentary written in carmina figurata.</decoNote></decoDesc><bindingDesc><binding><p> BM in-house. Brown leather.  Spine: 'Machazor Cum Comment. R. Josephi Kara Super Megilloth. Hebr. Mus. Brit. Jure Emptionis. 22,413.'</p></binding></bindingDesc></physDesc><history><origin><origDate notBefore="1300" notAfter="1329"/><origPlace>Germany</origPlace></origin><provenance>Acquisition: Adolphus Asher (b. 1800, d. 1853), Berlin bookseller and dealer to the British Museum (see 131-153): purchased by the British Museum from him on 12 June 1858: inscribed (168v). </provenance></history></msDesc></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><facsimile><surface n="78v" xml:id="surface-lewis-e-206-164"><graphic height="4412px" url="master/5506_0163.tif" width="3590px"/><graphic height="190px" url="thumb/5506_0163_thumb.jpg" width="154px"/><graphic height="1800px" url="web/5506_0163_web.jpg" width="1464px"/></surface></facsimile></TEI>