<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><teiHeader><fileDesc><titleStmt><title>Description of The revised recension of Maimonides' Sefer mitsṿot in the Hebrew translation of Mosheh ibn Tibon. </title><respStmt><resp>cataloger</resp><persName>Ilana Tahan</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>submitter</resp><persName>Agata Paluch</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>converted to OPenn TEI format</resp><orgName>Schoenberg Institute for Manuscript Studies</orgName></respStmt><funder>The Polonsky Foundation</funder></titleStmt><publicationStmt><publisher>The British Library</publisher><availability><licence target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">This metadata, accompanying images, and the content of
                                        London, British Library, Oriental Manuscripts Add MS 15421: The revised recension of Maimonides' Sefer mitsṿot in the Hebrew translation of Mosheh ibn Tibon.  are free of known
                                        copyright restrictions and in the public domain. See the
                                        Creative Commons Zero 1.0 Universal page for usage details,
                                        https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/.</licence><licence target="https://www.bl.uk/help/ethical-terms-of-use">
                                        The [British] Library respects the intellectual property
                                        rights, including moral rights, of rights holders and makes
                                        all reasonable effort to contact and consult rights owners,
                                        including, where appropriate, communities directly, or via
                                        local community organisations. Given the importance of the
                                        historical record, and the fact that that some of our
                                        digitised collections include materials that are sensitive
                                        to particular communities and groups, we ask that any use of
                                        the digitised collections is undertaken with the appropriate
                                        care. Irrespective of its copyright status, items and/or
                                        collections should not be altered or used in ways that might
                                        be derogatory to the originating individuals or communities.
                                        (Please follow the link for the complete text of the BL
                                        Ethical Terms of Use)</licence></availability></publicationStmt><notesStmt><note>
								Eli'ezer bar Yehudah ha-Rofe of L'Aquila: inscribed (folio 1r). A contract of sale, folio 140r, of the present manuscript by Refa'el ben Yitsḥaḳ ha-Rofe of Rieto to the heirs of Mosheh ha-Rofe of L'Aquila. Several censor's erasures, by Andrea del Monte (active in the second half of the 16th century), inscribed (folio 139v). </note><note type="relatedResource">
								Manuscript description based on Margoliouth, G.: Catalogue of the Hebrew and Samaritan Manuscripts in the British Museum, London 1965.
							</note></notesStmt><sourceDesc><msDesc><msIdentifier><country>United Kingdom</country><settlement>London</settlement><institution>British Library</institution><repository>Oriental Manuscripts</repository><collection>Hebrew Manuscripts Digitisation
                                            Project</collection><idno type="call-number">Add MS 15421</idno><altIdentifier type="resource"><idno>http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_15421</idno></altIdentifier><altIdentifier type="bl_website"><idno>https://www.bl.uk/hebrew-manuscripts</idno></altIdentifier></msIdentifier><msContents><summary>The revised recension of Maimonides' Sefer mitsṿot in the Hebrew translation of Mosheh ibn Tibon. </summary><textLang mainLang="he"/><msItem n="1r"><locus from="1r" to="140v">1r-140v</locus><title>Sefer ha-mitsṿot  ספר המצות </title></msItem></msContents><physDesc><objectDesc><supportDesc material="parchment"><support><p>Parchment</p></support><extent>140 folios  
									
								</extent><collation><p>
									14 quires of 10 leaves each. 
									Catchwords at the end of the quires, partly cut away. 
								</p></collation></supportDesc><layoutDesc><layout><p>Columns: 1 ;
                                                  ruled lines: 25;
                                                  written lines: 25; Uniform layout. Visible pricking and ruling with a hard-point object.  Last line written outside the ruling.  Marginal notes, occasionally mutilated in the trimming.  Sections enumerated with Hebrew letters in larger characters.  </p></layout></layoutDesc></objectDesc><scriptDesc><scriptNote>Italian semi-cursive script of the 15th century.  </scriptNote></scriptDesc><bindingDesc><binding><p> Post-1600. Black leather.  Spine title: 'Maimonides. Liber Preceptorum. Ex Versione Mosis ben Tibbon. Hebraice. Mus. Brit. Jure Emptionis 15,421. Plut.'</p></binding></bindingDesc></physDesc><history><origin><origDate when="1421"/><origPlace>Italy</origPlace></origin><provenance>Acquisition: 
								Thomas Rodd the younger (b. 1796, d. 1849): purchased from him by the British Museum on 18 January 1845, sale lot 295: inscribed (folio ).</provenance></history></msDesc></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><facsimile><surface n="78v" xml:id="surface-lewis-e-206-164"><graphic height="4412px" url="master/5506_0163.tif" width="3590px"/><graphic height="190px" url="thumb/5506_0163_thumb.jpg" width="154px"/><graphic height="1800px" url="web/5506_0163_web.jpg" width="1464px"/></surface></facsimile></TEI>