<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Description of A collection of prayers, a recension of the book of Tobit and Megilat Antiochus.</title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>cataloger</resp>
               <persName>Ilana Tahan</persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>submitter</resp>
               <persName>Agata Paluch</persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>converted to OPenn TEI format</resp>
               <orgName>Schoenberg Institute for Manuscript Studies</orgName>
            </respStmt>
            <funder>The Polonsky Foundation</funder>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The British Library</publisher>
            <availability>
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">This metadata, accompanying images, and the content of
                                        London, British Library, Oriental Manuscripts Harley MS 5713: A collection of prayers, a recension of the book of Tobit and Megilat Antiochus. are free of known
                                        copyright restrictions and in the public domain. See the
                                        Creative Commons Zero 1.0 Universal page for usage details,
                                        https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/.</licence>
               <licence target="https://www.bl.uk/help/ethical-terms-of-use">
                                        The [British] Library respects the intellectual property
                                        rights, including moral rights, of rights holders and makes
                                        all reasonable effort to contact and consult rights owners,
                                        including, where appropriate, communities directly, or via
                                        local community organisations. Given the importance of the
                                        historical record, and the fact that that some of our
                                        digitised collections include materials that are sensitive
                                        to particular communities and groups, we ask that any use of
                                        the digitised collections is undertaken with the appropriate
                                        care. Irrespective of its copyright status, items and/or
                                        collections should not be altered or used in ways that might
                                        be derogatory to the originating individuals or communities.
                                        (Please follow the link for the complete text of the BL
                                        Ethical Terms of Use)</licence>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>Folios 19r, 20r: a scribal note of Aharon ben Mosheh, who came to England from Vilnius (The Kingdom of Poland and Lithuania), but was born in Nowogrodek.
								Humphrey Wanley, (b. 1672, d. 1726), Old English scholar and the librarian to the Earls of Oxford. As Queen Anne was the subject of the Royal Prayer, the manuscript must have been completed before 01 August 1714.</note>
            <note type="relatedResource">
								Manuscript description based on Margoliouth, G.: Catalogue of the Hebrew and Samaritan Manuscripts in the British Museum, London 1965.
							</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <country>United Kingdom</country>
                  <settlement>London</settlement>
                  <institution>British Library</institution>
                  <repository>Oriental Manuscripts</repository>
                  <collection>Hebrew Manuscripts Digitisation
                                            Project</collection>
                  <idno type="call-number">Harley MS 5713</idno>
                  <altIdentifier type="resource">
                     <idno>http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Harley_MS_5713</idno>
                  </altIdentifier>
                  <altIdentifier type="bl_website">
                     <idno>https://www.bl.uk/hebrew-manuscripts</idno>
                  </altIdentifier>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>A collection of prayers, a recension of the book of Tobit and Megilat Antiochus.</summary>
                  <textLang mainLang="he">Hebrew</textLang>
                  <msItem n="1r">
                     <locus from="1r" to="20v">1r-20v</locus>
                     <title>Tefilot תפילות</title>
                  </msItem>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc material="parchment">
                        <support>
                           <p>Parchment</p>
                        </support>
                        <extent>20 folios 
								</extent>
                        <collation>
                           <p>
									Quires of mostly 10 leaves each.
								</p>
                        </collation>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <p>Columns: 1 ;
                                                  ruled lines: 14;
                                                  written lines: 13; Uniform layout. Visible hard-point ruling.Initial words written in larger characters. Hair side and flesh side of the folios indistinguishable.Parts of the text written in red ink.</p>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <scriptDesc>
                     <scriptNote>Ashkenazi square script, punctuated, of the 18th century. Aharon ben Mosheh of Poland: inscribed with his name, folio 19r, 20r.</scriptNote>
                  </scriptDesc>
                  <decoDesc>
                     <decoNote type="border">
                        <locus>1r</locus>
								1 illustrated title-page with pen flourishings, in colours.</decoNote>
                     <decoNote type="illustration">
                        <locus>4r</locus>Numerous text illustrations, in colours.
							</decoNote>
                     <decoNote type="illustration">
                        <locus>4v</locus>Numerous text illustrations, in colours.
							</decoNote>
                     <decoNote type="illustration">
                        <locus>5v</locus>Numerous text illustrations, in colours.
							</decoNote>
                     <decoNote type="illustration">
                        <locus>9r</locus>Numerous text illustrations, in colours.
							</decoNote>
                     <decoNote type="illustration">
                        <locus>10r</locus>Numerous text illustrations, in colours.
							</decoNote>
                     <decoNote type="illustration">
                        <locus>17r</locus>Numerous text illustrations, in colours.
							</decoNote>
                     <decoNote type="illustration">
                        <locus>17v</locus>Numerous text illustrations, in colours.
							</decoNote>
                     <decoNote type="illustration">
                        <locus>18r</locus>Numerous text illustrations, in colours.
							</decoNote>
                     <decoNote type="illustration">
                        <locus>19r</locus>Numerous text illustrations, in colours.
							</decoNote>
                     <decoNote type="illustration">
                        <locus>20r</locus>Numerous text illustrations, in colours.
							</decoNote>
                     <decoNote type="illustration">
                        <locus>11v</locus>
								1 full-page drawing of a candlestick, with parts of text embodied, in colours.</decoNote>
                  </decoDesc>
                  <bindingDesc>
                     <binding>
                        <p> Post-1600. Harleian binding. Spine: 'Preces. Liber Tobiae. Et Alia. Hebraice. Mus. Brit. Bibl. Harl. 5713. Plut XXXI F.'</p>
                     </binding>
                  </bindingDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="1702" notAfter="1714"/>
                     <origPlace>England</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>Acquisition: The Harley Collection, formed by Robert Harley (b. 1661, d. 1724), 1st earl of Oxford and Mortimer, politician, and Edward Harley (b. 1689, d. 1741), 2nd earl of Oxford and Mortimer, book collector and patron of the arts.
Edward Harley bequeathed the library to his widow, Henrietta Cavendish, née Holles (b. 1694, d. 1755) during her lifetime and thereafter to their daughter, Margaret Cavendish Bentinck (b. 1715, d.1785), duchess of Portland; the manuscripts were sold by the Countess and the Duchess in 1753 to the nation for £10,000 (a fraction of their contemporary value) under the Act of Parliament that also established the British Museum; the Harley manuscripts form one of the foundation collections of the British Library.</provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <facsimile>
      <surface n="78v" xml:id="surface-lewis-e-206-164">
         <graphic height="4412px" url="master/5506_0163.tif" width="3590px"/>
         <graphic height="190px" url="thumb/5506_0163_thumb.jpg" width="154px"/>
         <graphic height="1800px" url="web/5506_0163_web.jpg" width="1464px"/>
      </surface>
   </facsimile>
</TEI>
