<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><teiHeader><fileDesc><titleStmt><title>Description of Levi ben Gershom's Supercommentary on Ibn Rushd's Intermediate Commentary on Porphyry's Introduction to the Organon of Aristotle.</title><respStmt><resp>cataloger</resp><persName>Ilana Tahan</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>submitter</resp><persName>Agata Paluch</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>converted to OPenn TEI format</resp><orgName>Schoenberg Institute for Manuscript Studies</orgName></respStmt><funder>The Polonsky Foundation</funder></titleStmt><publicationStmt><publisher>The British Library</publisher><availability><licence target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">This metadata, accompanying images, and the content of
                                        London, British Library, Oriental Manuscripts Add MS 18687: Levi ben Gershom's Supercommentary on Ibn Rushd's Intermediate Commentary on Porphyry's Introduction to the Organon of Aristotle. are free of known
                                        copyright restrictions and in the public domain. See the
                                        Creative Commons Zero 1.0 Universal page for usage details,
                                        https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/.</licence><licence target="https://www.bl.uk/help/ethical-terms-of-use">
                                        The [British] Library respects the intellectual property
                                        rights, including moral rights, of rights holders and makes
                                        all reasonable effort to contact and consult rights owners,
                                        including, where appropriate, communities directly, or via
                                        local community organisations. Given the importance of the
                                        historical record, and the fact that that some of our
                                        digitised collections include materials that are sensitive
                                        to particular communities and groups, we ask that any use of
                                        the digitised collections is undertaken with the appropriate
                                        care. Irrespective of its copyright status, items and/or
                                        collections should not be altered or used in ways that might
                                        be derogatory to the originating individuals or communities.
                                        (Please follow the link for the complete text of the BL
                                        Ethical Terms of Use)</licence></availability></publicationStmt><notesStmt><note>Damp at head (in part).  Old losses infilled.  Stained.</note><note>Two additional fragmentary pieces appended: folios 185r-190v, Be᾿ur ha-melitsah, an exposition on the earlier portions of the second book of the Organon, and folios 190v-191v, Levi ben Gershom's notes 1-4 on the Intermediate Commentary of Averroes on Porphyry's Introduction to the Organon.</note><note type="relatedResource">
								
                        
                        
                        
                        Manuscript description based on Margoliouth, G.: Catalogue of the Hebrew and Samaritan Manuscripts in the British Museum, London 1965.
							
                     
                     
                     
                     </note></notesStmt><sourceDesc><msDesc><msIdentifier><country>United Kingdom</country><settlement>London</settlement><institution>British Library</institution><repository>Oriental Manuscripts</repository><collection>Hebrew Manuscripts Digitisation
                                            Project</collection><idno type="call-number">Add MS 18687</idno><altIdentifier type="resource"><idno>http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_18687</idno></altIdentifier><altIdentifier type="bl_website"><idno>https://www.bl.uk/hebrew-manuscripts</idno></altIdentifier></msIdentifier><msContents><summary>Levi ben Gershom's Supercommentary on Ibn Rushd's Intermediate Commentary on Porphyry's Introduction to the Organon of Aristotle.</summary><textLang mainLang="he"/><msItem n="1r"><locus from="1r" to="191v">1r-191v</locus><title>Perush ῾al Be᾿ur ha-emtsa῾i shel Ibn Rushd ῾al Sifre ha-higayon shel Aristo פרוש על הבאור האמצעי של אבן רשד על ספרי ההגיון של אריסטו</title></msItem></msContents><physDesc><objectDesc><supportDesc material="parchment"><support><p>Parchment</p></support><extent>191 folios
									
                           
                           
                           
                           
								
                        
                        
                        
                        </extent><collation><p>
									
                           
                           
                           
                           24 quires of 8 leaves each (last quire missing 1 leaf), marked with catchwords at the end, and also at the end of each of the first three leaves of ach quire.
								
                        
                        
                        
                        </p></collation></supportDesc><layoutDesc><layout><p>Columns: 1 ;
                                                  ruled lines: 23;
                                                  written lines: 23; Uniform layout.Titles and inital words in larger characters. First words and upward or downward strokes of letters on the first and last lines of pages respectively are sometimes ornamented, e.g., folio 81v, 82r, 136v, 137r.Visible hard-point ruling.Flesh side and hair side distinguishable.A small circle drawn on the right-hand upper corner of the first leaf of a quire, e.g., folio 33r, 41r.Marginal notes.Maniculae, e.g., folio 74r, 75v, 77v, 97v, etc.Folio 1 is a title page.</p></layout></layoutDesc></objectDesc><scriptDesc><scriptNote>Sefardi square and semi-curive script of the 15th century. Ḥayim Porovintsal (Provenzal): inscribed with his name in the colophon, folio 184v.</scriptNote></scriptDesc><bindingDesc><binding><p> BM in-house. Spine: 'Levi ben Gershon. Supercommentary Upon Ibn Rushd. Hebrew. Brit. Mus. Additional 18,687.'</p></binding></bindingDesc></physDesc><history><origin><origDate when="1459"/></origin><provenance>Mosheh ben Yeḥiel ha-Rofe</provenance><provenance>David ben Solomon Altaras</provenance><provenance>Acquisition: 
								
                        
                        
                        
                        Adolphus Asher (b. 1800, d. 1853), Berlin bookseller and dealer to the British Museum 1841-1853: purchased from him by the British Museum on 24 April 1851: inscribed, folio [192v] (fse005v).</provenance></history></msDesc></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><facsimile><surface n="78v" xml:id="surface-lewis-e-206-164"><graphic height="4412px" url="master/5506_0163.tif" width="3590px"/><graphic height="190px" url="thumb/5506_0163_thumb.jpg" width="154px"/><graphic height="1800px" url="web/5506_0163_web.jpg" width="1464px"/></surface></facsimile></TEI>