<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Description of Ketuvim (כתובים)</title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>cataloger</resp>
               <persName>Ilana Tahan</persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>submitter</resp>
               <persName>Agata Paluch</persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>converted to OPenn TEI format</resp>
               <orgName>Schoenberg Institute for Manuscript Studies</orgName>
            </respStmt>
            <funder>The Polonsky Foundation</funder>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The British Library</publisher>
            <availability>
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">This metadata, accompanying images, and the content of
                                        London, British Library, Oriental Manuscripts Harley MS 5715: Ketuvim  are free of known
                                        copyright restrictions and in the public domain. See the
                                        Creative Commons Zero 1.0 Universal page for usage details,
                                        https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/.</licence>
               <licence target="https://www.bl.uk/help/ethical-terms-of-use">
                                        The [British] Library respects the intellectual property
                                        rights, including moral rights, of rights holders and makes
                                        all reasonable effort to contact and consult rights owners,
                                        including, where appropriate, communities directly, or via
                                        local community organisations. Given the importance of the
                                        historical record, and the fact that that some of our
                                        digitised collections include materials that are sensitive
                                        to particular communities and groups, we ask that any use of
                                        the digitised collections is undertaken with the appropriate
                                        care. Irrespective of its copyright status, items and/or
                                        collections should not be altered or used in ways that might
                                        be derogatory to the originating individuals or communities.
                                        (Please follow the link for the complete text of the BL
                                        Ethical Terms of Use)</licence>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>Imperfect at the beginning.</note>
            <note>Several records of sale by: Yudah ben Shelomoh (seller); Eliyahu, Shemuʾel, Zidkiyahu and Avraham ben Mosheh (buyers); Shelomoh ben Yeḳutiʾel da Bethel (buyer); Benyamin ben Yoʾav (buyer); Daniel ben Yeḥiʾel  of Montalcino (buyer, inscribed with a date of 5135, 1375 in Perugia); and an attestation of Yeḥiʾel  ben Meshullam the scribe and Benyamin ben Manoaḥ to the sale of the present manuscript by the lady Brunetta, widow of Daniel of Motalcino, to Mordekhai ben Mosheh (buyer, with a date of 5162, 1401 in Perugia on the Tiber); inscribed on folio . An English translation of the first three contracts, and an account of the last two, are attached to the paper fly-leaf at the end of the codex ().</note>
            <note type="relatedResource">
								Manuscript description based on Margoliouth, G.: Catalogue of the Hebrew and Samaritan Manuscripts in the British Museum, London 1965.
							</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <country>United Kingdom</country>
                  <settlement>London</settlement>
                  <institution>British Library</institution>
                  <repository>Oriental Manuscripts</repository>
                  <collection>Hebrew Manuscripts Digitisation
                                            Project</collection>
                  <idno type="call-number">Harley MS 5715</idno>
                  <altIdentifier type="resource">
                     <idno>http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Harley_MS_5715</idno>
                  </altIdentifier>
                  <altIdentifier type="bl_website">
                     <idno>https://www.bl.uk/hebrew-manuscripts</idno>
                  </altIdentifier>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>The Hagiographa, provided with vowel-points and accents.</summary>
                  <textLang mainLang="he">Hebrew</textLang>
                  <msItem n="1r">
                     <locus from="1r" to="165v">1r-165v</locus>
                     <title>Ketuvim  כתובים  </title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="1r">
                     <locus from="1r" to="35v">1r-35v</locus>
                     <title>Psalms</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="36r">
                     <locus from="36r" to="52v">36r-52v</locus>
                     <title>Proverbs</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="52v">
                     <locus from="52v" to="69v">52v-69v</locus>
                     <title>Job</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="69v">
                     <locus from="69v" to="80v">69v-80v</locus>
                     <title>Daniel</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="80v">
                     <locus from="80v" to="99r">80v-99r</locus>
                     <title>Ezra</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="99v">
                     <locus from="99v" to="146r">99v-146r</locus>
                     <title>Chronicles</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="146r">
                     <locus from="146r" to="148v">146r-148v</locus>
                     <title>Ruth</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="148v">
                     <locus from="148v" to="151r">148v-151r</locus>
                     <title>Song of Songs</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="151r">
                     <locus from="151r" to="156r">151r-156r</locus>
                     <title>Ecclesiastes</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="156r">
                     <locus from="156r" to="162r">156r-162r</locus>
                     <title>Esther</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="162r">
                     <locus from="162r" to="165r">162r-165r</locus>
                     <title>Lamentations</title>
                  </msItem>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc material="parchment">
                        <support>
                           <p>Parchment</p>
                        </support>
                        <extent>165 folios
									
								</extent>
                        <collation>
                           <p>
									 	Quires of mostly 8 leaves each.
								</p>
                        </collation>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <p>Columns: 2;
                                                  ruled lines: 25;
                                                  written lines: 25; Uniform layout. Pencil ruling and occasionally pricking is visible. Chronicles and Esther begin a new column, and Proverbs opens a new leaf. If there is not sufficient room in a line to complete the last word, the final letter or the last two letters of the same word are placed in the margin, some vacant space being left between the columns and these letters. The number of Psalms is 151 (number 96 is divided into two parts). Few masoretic notes. </p>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <scriptDesc>
                     <scriptNote>Sefardi square script, punctuated and accentuated, of early 14th century.</scriptNote>
                  </scriptDesc>
                  <bindingDesc>
                     <binding>
                        <p> Post-1600, Harleian binding of gold-tooled brown leather. Boxed.</p>
                     </binding>
                  </bindingDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="1300" notAfter="1340"/>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>Acquisition: The Harley Collection, formed by Robert Harley (b. 1661, d. 1724), 1st earl of Oxford and Mortimer, politician, and Edward Harley (b. 1689, d. 1741), 2nd earl of Oxford and Mortimer, book collector and patron of the arts. Edward Harley bequeathed the library to his widow, Henrietta Cavendish, née Holles (b. 1694, d. 1755) during her lifetime and thereafter to their daughter, Margaret Cavendish Bentinck (b. 1715, d. 1785), duchess of Portland; the manuscripts were sold by the Countess and the Duchess in 1753 to the nation for £10,000 (a fraction of their contemporary value) under the Act of Parliament that also established the British Museum; the Harley manuscripts form one of the foundation collections of the British Library.</provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <facsimile>
      <surface n="78v" xml:id="surface-lewis-e-206-164">
         <graphic height="4412px" url="master/5506_0163.tif" width="3590px"/>
         <graphic height="190px" url="thumb/5506_0163_thumb.jpg" width="154px"/>
         <graphic height="1800px" url="web/5506_0163_web.jpg" width="1464px"/>
      </surface>
   </facsimile>
</TEI>
