<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><teiHeader><fileDesc><titleStmt><title>Description of The second part of Sefer mitsṿot gadol of Moses ben Jacob of Coucy.</title><respStmt><resp>cataloger</resp><persName>Ilana Tahan</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>submitter</resp><persName>Agata Paluch</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>converted to OPenn TEI format</resp><orgName>Schoenberg Institute for Manuscript Studies</orgName></respStmt><funder>The Polonsky Foundation</funder></titleStmt><publicationStmt><publisher>The British Library</publisher><availability><licence target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">This metadata, accompanying images, and the content of
                                        London, British Library, Oriental Manuscripts Or 1081: The second part of Sefer mitsṿot gadol of Moses ben Jacob of Coucy. are free of known
                                        copyright restrictions and in the public domain. See the
                                        Creative Commons Zero 1.0 Universal page for usage details,
                                        https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/.</licence><licence target="https://www.bl.uk/help/ethical-terms-of-use">
                                        The [British] Library respects the intellectual property
                                        rights, including moral rights, of rights holders and makes
                                        all reasonable effort to contact and consult rights owners,
                                        including, where appropriate, communities directly, or via
                                        local community organisations. Given the importance of the
                                        historical record, and the fact that that some of our
                                        digitised collections include materials that are sensitive
                                        to particular communities and groups, we ask that any use of
                                        the digitised collections is undertaken with the appropriate
                                        care. Irrespective of its copyright status, items and/or
                                        collections should not be altered or used in ways that might
                                        be derogatory to the originating individuals or communities.
                                        (Please follow the link for the complete text of the BL
                                        Ethical Terms of Use)</licence></availability></publicationStmt><notesStmt><note>Imperfect at the beginning. </note><note>A note relating to a confiscation and subsequent return of the manuscript to Scuola Pugliesa, a synagogue on Corfu belonging to the Apulian community: dated 1772  (folio 1r). 
								Yosef ben Avraham Boleli: inscribed (folio 246v). </note><note type="relatedResource">
								Manuscript description based on Margoliouth, G.: Catalogue of the Hebrew and Samaritan Manuscripts in the British Museum, London 1965.
							</note></notesStmt><sourceDesc><msDesc><msIdentifier><country>United Kingdom</country><settlement>London</settlement><institution>British Library</institution><repository>Oriental Manuscripts</repository><collection>Hebrew Manuscripts Digitisation
                                            Project</collection><idno type="call-number">Or 1081</idno><altIdentifier type="resource"><idno>http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Or_1081</idno></altIdentifier><altIdentifier type="bl_website"><idno>https://www.bl.uk/hebrew-manuscripts</idno></altIdentifier></msIdentifier><msContents><summary>The second part of Sefer mitsṿot gadol of Moses ben Jacob of Coucy.</summary><textLang mainLang="he"/><msItem n="1r"><locus from="1r" to="336v">1r-336v</locus><title>Sefer mitsṿot gadol ספר מצוות גדול</title></msItem></msContents><physDesc><objectDesc><supportDesc material="parchment"><support><p>Parchment</p></support><extent>336 folios 
									
								</extent><collation><p>
									Currently 21 quires of 16 leaves each, followed by a single leaf at the end. 
									A complete quire appears to be missing at the beginning. 
								</p></collation></supportDesc><layoutDesc><layout><p>Columns: 1 ;
                                                  ruled lines: 29 41;
                                                  written lines: 29 41; Uniform layout. Last line written within ruling. Hard-point ruling visible (frame only), leaf by leaf on recto. Hair-side and fleash-side of the folios distinguishable. Occasional marginal notes. Chapter initials and titles given in larger characters. Catchwords on every verso. A simple pen and ink drawing below one of the catchwords, folio 46v. Occasional infralinear vocalization. </p></layout></layoutDesc></objectDesc><scriptDesc><scriptNote>Byzantine square and semi-cursive script of the 14th century. Mosheh: marked off in an acrostic, folio 336v. </scriptNote></scriptDesc><bindingDesc><binding><p> BM in-house.  Spine title: 'Moses of Coucy. Sefer Misvoth Gadhol. A.D. 1390. Hebrew. Brit. Mus. Oriental 1081.'</p></binding></bindingDesc></physDesc><history><origin><origDate when="1390"/><origPlace>Corfu</origPlace></origin></history></msDesc></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><facsimile><surface n="78v" xml:id="surface-lewis-e-206-164"><graphic height="4412px" url="master/5506_0163.tif" width="3590px"/><graphic height="190px" url="thumb/5506_0163_thumb.jpg" width="154px"/><graphic height="1800px" url="web/5506_0163_web.jpg" width="1464px"/></surface></facsimile></TEI>