<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><teiHeader><fileDesc><titleStmt><title>Description of Grammatical writing.</title><respStmt><resp>cataloger</resp><persName>Ilana Tahan</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>submitter</resp><persName>Agata Paluch</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>converted to OPenn TEI format</resp><orgName>Schoenberg Institute for Manuscript Studies</orgName></respStmt><funder>The Polonsky Foundation</funder></titleStmt><publicationStmt><publisher>The British Library</publisher><availability><licence target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">This metadata, accompanying images, and the content of
                                        London, British Library, Oriental Manuscripts Harley MS 5531: Grammatical writing. are free of known
                                        copyright restrictions and in the public domain. See the
                                        Creative Commons Zero 1.0 Universal page for usage details,
                                        https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/.</licence><licence target="https://www.bl.uk/help/ethical-terms-of-use">
                                        The [British] Library respects the intellectual property
                                        rights, including moral rights, of rights holders and makes
                                        all reasonable effort to contact and consult rights owners,
                                        including, where appropriate, communities directly, or via
                                        local community organisations. Given the importance of the
                                        historical record, and the fact that that some of our
                                        digitised collections include materials that are sensitive
                                        to particular communities and groups, we ask that any use of
                                        the digitised collections is undertaken with the appropriate
                                        care. Irrespective of its copyright status, items and/or
                                        collections should not be altered or used in ways that might
                                        be derogatory to the originating individuals or communities.
                                        (Please follow the link for the complete text of the BL
                                        Ethical Terms of Use)</licence></availability></publicationStmt><notesStmt><note>Inscription in Latin about the content of the codex: ‘Dictionarium Herbaicum Joseph figlii.. .. ' (18th century) (folio 2r).
Inscription in English: ‘This Book called Baal Lashon i.e. Master of Language is an Hebrew Dictionary composed by R. Joseph Zark in the year 5208 × 1448 in Italy it is divided into 3 parts first words composed of two letters 2nd by words composed of 3 letters 3 by letters composed of four or more letters. Never printed. Same book with 5502. (BM note, folio [ii verso]).
Inscription in English: ‘Those two names of the authors’ Benefactors, which had been erased in the manuscript, are here restored in the margin from codex 5502. pag. 2.' (BM note); the mentioned names are added in Hebrew in the outer margin: Mordekhai and Yitshak, Avraham, Shelomoh Finzi (folio 6r).</note><note type="relatedResource">
                        
                        
                        
                        Manuscript description based on Margoliouth, G.: Catalogue of the Hebrew and Samaritan Manuscripts in the British Museum, London 1965.
                     
                     
                     
                     </note></notesStmt><sourceDesc><msDesc><msIdentifier><country>United Kingdom</country><settlement>London</settlement><institution>British Library</institution><repository>Oriental Manuscripts</repository><collection>Hebrew Manuscripts Digitisation
                                            Project</collection><idno type="call-number">Harley MS 5531</idno><altIdentifier type="resource"><idno>http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Harley_MS_5531</idno></altIdentifier><altIdentifier type="bl_website"><idno>https://www.bl.uk/hebrew-manuscripts</idno></altIdentifier></msIdentifier><msContents><summary>Grammatical writing.</summary><textLang mainLang="he"/><msItem n="1r"><locus from="1r" to="286v">1r-286v</locus><title>Ba῾al ha-lashon בעל הלשון</title></msItem></msContents><physDesc><objectDesc><supportDesc material="parchment"><support><p>Parchment</p></support><extent>286 folios
                           
                           
                           
                           
                        
                        
                        
                        </extent><collation><p>
                           
                           
                           
                           30 quires: i8 (folios 2-3), ii-xxix10 (folios 4-283), xxx6 (folios  284-[289]), marked with Hebrew letters at the end.
                        
                        
                        
                        </p></collation></supportDesc><layoutDesc><layout><p>Columns: 1;
                                                  ruled lines: 26;
                                                  written lines: 26; Uniform layout.Emblem, probably of the family Modigliani of Rome (see 178-179.3 unfoliated blank leaves at the end folios [287]-[289]. Six unfoliated blank leaves after folio 2r. Quires are numbered with Hebrew characters starting with alef on folio 13v until folio 163v. Flesh side and hair side are distinguishable. Horizontal ink ruling and vertical plummet ruling is visible. Traces of pricking.Titles and inital words in larger square characters. </p></layout></layoutDesc></objectDesc><scriptDesc><scriptNote>Ashkenazi square and semi-cursive script, partially punctuated, of the latter part of the 15th century.</scriptNote></scriptDesc><decoDesc><decoNote type="initial">Numerous initial-word panels with pen-flourishing sometimes with masks, in violet ink. 
                     
                     
                     
                     </decoNote><decoNote type="initial"><locus>8v</locus>2 initial-word panels formed as a castle. 
                     
                     
                     
                     </decoNote><decoNote type="initial"><locus>17v</locus>2 initial-word panels formed as a castle. 
                     
                     
                     
                     </decoNote><decoNote type="illustration"><locus>18v</locus>Crown over an initial word, in violet ink . 
                     
                     
                     
                     </decoNote><decoNote type="marginal"><locus>6v</locus>Marginal drawings, in violet and light brown ink.
                     
                     
                     
                     </decoNote><decoNote type="marginal"><locus>7r</locus>Marginal drawings, in violet and light brown ink.
                     
                     
                     
                     </decoNote><decoNote type="marginal"><locus>17v</locus>Marginal drawings, in violet and light brown ink.
                     
                     
                     
                     </decoNote></decoDesc><bindingDesc><binding><p> Post-1600. Morroco leather, gold tooled. Spine: 'Joseph Zark. Ba'al Hallashon. Hebrew. Brit. Mus. Harley Or. 5531.'</p></binding></bindingDesc></physDesc><history><origin><origDate when="1474"/></origin><provenance>Nathaniel Noel</provenance><provenance>Edward Harley</provenance><provenance>Acquisition: The Harley Collection, formed by Robert Harley (b. 1661, d. 1724), 1st earl of Oxford and Mortimer, politician, and Edward Harley (b. 1689, d. 1741), 2nd earl of Oxford and Mortimer, book collector and patron of the arts.
Edward Harley bequeathed the library to his widow, Henrietta Cavendish, née Holles (b. 1694, d. 1755) during her lifetime and thereafter to their daughter, Margaret Cavendish Bentick (b. 1715, d.1785), Duchess of Portland; the manuscripts were sold by the Countess and the Duchess in 1753 to the nation for £10,000 (a fraction of their contemporary value) under the Act of Parliament that also established the British Museum; the Harley manuscripts form one of the foundation collections of the British Library.</provenance></history></msDesc></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><facsimile><surface n="78v" xml:id="surface-lewis-e-206-164"><graphic height="4412px" url="master/5506_0163.tif" width="3590px"/><graphic height="190px" url="thumb/5506_0163_thumb.jpg" width="154px"/><graphic height="1800px" url="web/5506_0163_web.jpg" width="1464px"/></surface></facsimile></TEI>