<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><teiHeader><fileDesc><titleStmt><title>Description of A collection of kabbalistic texts, consisting of two originally distinct manuscripts.</title><respStmt><resp>cataloger</resp><persName>Ilana Tahan</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>submitter</resp><persName>Agata Paluch</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>converted to OPenn TEI format</resp><orgName>Schoenberg Institute for Manuscript Studies</orgName></respStmt><funder>The Polonsky Foundation</funder></titleStmt><publicationStmt><publisher>The British Library</publisher><availability><licence target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">This metadata, accompanying images, and the content of
                                        London, British Library, Oriental Manuscripts Add MS 27009: A collection of kabbalistic texts, consisting of two originally distinct manuscripts. are free of known
                                        copyright restrictions and in the public domain. See the
                                        Creative Commons Zero 1.0 Universal page for usage details,
                                        https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/.</licence><licence target="https://www.bl.uk/help/ethical-terms-of-use">
                                        The [British] Library respects the intellectual property
                                        rights, including moral rights, of rights holders and makes
                                        all reasonable effort to contact and consult rights owners,
                                        including, where appropriate, communities directly, or via
                                        local community organisations. Given the importance of the
                                        historical record, and the fact that that some of our
                                        digitised collections include materials that are sensitive
                                        to particular communities and groups, we ask that any use of
                                        the digitised collections is undertaken with the appropriate
                                        care. Irrespective of its copyright status, items and/or
                                        collections should not be altered or used in ways that might
                                        be derogatory to the originating individuals or communities.
                                        (Please follow the link for the complete text of the BL
                                        Ethical Terms of Use)</licence></availability></publicationStmt><notesStmt><note>Stained. Water-damaged. First leaf injured. Heavily water-damaged.</note><note>Folio 106r (a vellum end flyleaf): a note in Italian semi-cursive script of the 15th century, headed 'de῾ot ha-filosofim').</note><note type="relatedResource">
								
                        
                        
                        
                        Manuscript description based on Margoliouth, G.: Catalogue of the Hebrew and Samaritan Manuscripts in the British Museum, London 1965.
							
                     
                     
                     
                     </note></notesStmt><sourceDesc><msDesc><msIdentifier><country>United Kingdom</country><settlement>London</settlement><institution>British Library</institution><repository>Oriental Manuscripts</repository><collection>Hebrew Manuscripts Digitisation
                                            Project</collection><idno type="call-number">Add MS 27009</idno><altIdentifier type="resource"><idno>http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_27009</idno></altIdentifier><altIdentifier type="bl_website"><idno>https://www.bl.uk/hebrew-manuscripts</idno></altIdentifier></msIdentifier><msContents><summary>A collection of kabbalistic texts, consisting of two originally distinct manuscripts.</summary><textLang mainLang="he" otherLangs="tmr-Hebr"/><msItem n="1r"><locus from="1r" to="59v">1r-59v</locus><title>Perush ha-tefilot פרוש התפלות</title></msItem><msItem n="60r"><locus from="60r" to="105v">60r-105v</locus><title>Zohar ḥadash (midrash Rut) זהר חדש (מדרש רות)</title></msItem></msContents><physDesc><objectDesc><supportDesc material="paper"><support><p>Paper</p></support><extent>
								106 folios (+ 3 unfoliated paper flyleaf at the beginning and 3 at the end).
								60 folios
										
                              
                              
                              
                              
									
                           
                           
                           
                           45 folios
										
                              
                              
                              
                              
									
                           
                           
                           
                           </extent><collation><p>
										
                              
                              
                              
                              Quires of mostly 8 leaves each. 2 inner quires are parchment, the rest is paper.
									
                           
                           
                           
                           
										
                              
                              
                              
                              One complete quire of 16 leaves (folios 60-75), one quire of 15 leaves (folios 76-90, missing one leaf at the beginning), and the last quire of 15 leaves (folios 91-105, missing one leaf at the end).
									
                           
                           
                           
                           </p></collation></supportDesc><layoutDesc><layout><p>Columns: 1 1;
                                                  ruled lines: 24 24;
                                                  written lines: 24 24; Uniform layout.Instead of catchwords, catch-letters are used, the first letter of the first word of a folio being written at the end of the preceding page.Many corrections and variant readings have been supplied in the margin.Uniform layuot.Initial words written in square characters.Catchwords from folio to folio, those at the end of quires being distinguished by an accompanying small pen and ink design.Additional notes and comments supplied in the margin.</p></layout></layoutDesc></objectDesc><scriptDesc><scriptNote>Italian and Sefardi semi-cursive scripts of the 15th century. Italian semi-cursive script of the 15th century. Sefardi semi-cursive of the 15th century.</scriptNote></scriptDesc><bindingDesc><binding><p> BM/BL in-house. Spine: 'Perush Hat-Tephilloth. Etc. Hebrew. Brit. Mus. Additional 27,009.'</p></binding></bindingDesc></physDesc><history><origin><origDate notBefore="1400" notAfter="1499"/></origin><provenance>Acquisition: 
								
                        
                        
                        
                        Giuseppe Almanzi (b. 1801, d. 1860), bibliophile his manuscript no. 119; his library including 322 medieval Hebrew manuscripts were purchased en bloc by the British Museum through Asher &amp; Co. in October 1865 for £1,000 through Asher &amp; Co., Berlin dealer to the British Museum (see 131-153); inscribed, folio [107v].</provenance></history></msDesc></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><facsimile><surface n="78v" xml:id="surface-lewis-e-206-164"><graphic height="4412px" url="master/5506_0163.tif" width="3590px"/><graphic height="190px" url="thumb/5506_0163_thumb.jpg" width="154px"/><graphic height="1800px" url="web/5506_0163_web.jpg" width="1464px"/></surface></facsimile></TEI>