<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><teiHeader><fileDesc><titleStmt><title>Description of תורה(Torah)</title><respStmt><resp>cataloger</resp><persName>Ilana Tahan</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>submitter</resp><persName>Agata Paluch</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>converted to OPenn TEI format</resp><orgName>Schoenberg Institute for Manuscript Studies</orgName></respStmt><funder>The Polonsky Foundation</funder></titleStmt><publicationStmt><publisher>The British Library</publisher><availability><licence target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">This metadata, accompanying images, and the content of
                                        London, British Library, Oriental Manuscripts Harley MS 5586: תורה are free of known
                                        copyright restrictions and in the public domain. See the
                                        Creative Commons Zero 1.0 Universal page for usage details,
                                        https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/.</licence><licence target="https://www.bl.uk/help/ethical-terms-of-use">
                                        The [British] Library respects the intellectual property
                                        rights, including moral rights, of rights holders and makes
                                        all reasonable effort to contact and consult rights owners,
                                        including, where appropriate, communities directly, or via
                                        local community organisations. Given the importance of the
                                        historical record, and the fact that that some of our
                                        digitised collections include materials that are sensitive
                                        to particular communities and groups, we ask that any use of
                                        the digitised collections is undertaken with the appropriate
                                        care. Irrespective of its copyright status, items and/or
                                        collections should not be altered or used in ways that might
                                        be derogatory to the originating individuals or communities.
                                        (Please follow the link for the complete text of the BL
                                        Ethical Terms of Use)</licence></availability></publicationStmt><notesStmt><note>
								Avraham ben Shelomoh of Fano, inscribed with his name on folio 1v, לה' הארץ ומלואה הגיע לחלק אברהם מפאנו בכר' שלמה מפאנו ז"ל.        
								Eliezer ben Avraham and Shelomoh of Fano, previous owners of this manuscript, also recorded on folio 1v.
								Edward Harley: inscription by Harley's librarian, Humfrey Wanley, 18 January 1723/4 (folio 1r). </note><note type="relatedResource">
								Manuscript description based on Margoliouth, G.: Catalogue of the Hebrew and Samaritan Manuscripts in the British Museum, London 1965.
							</note></notesStmt><sourceDesc><msDesc><msIdentifier><country>United Kingdom</country><settlement>London</settlement><institution>British Library</institution><repository>Oriental Manuscripts</repository><collection>Hebrew Manuscripts Digitisation
                                            Project</collection><idno type="call-number">Harley MS 5586</idno><altIdentifier type="resource"><idno>http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Harley_MS_5586</idno></altIdentifier><altIdentifier type="bl_website"><idno>https://www.bl.uk/hebrew-manuscripts</idno></altIdentifier></msIdentifier><msContents><summary>Pentateuch provided with vowel-points and accents, accompanied by Masorah magna and parva. </summary><textLang mainLang="he"/><msItem n="2r"><locus from="2r" to="170v">2r-170v</locus><title>תורה Torah Pentateuch</title></msItem><msItem n="2r"><locus from="2r" to="43r">2r-43r</locus><title>Genesis</title></msItem><msItem n="43r"><locus from="43r" to="78v">43r-78v</locus><title>Exodus</title></msItem><msItem n="78v"><locus from="78v" to="103v">78v-103v</locus><title>Leviticus</title></msItem><msItem n="103v"><locus from="103v" to="140r">103v-140r</locus><title>Numbers</title></msItem><msItem n="140r"><locus from="140r" to="170v">140r-170v</locus><title>Deuteronomy</title></msItem></msContents><physDesc><objectDesc><supportDesc material="parchment"><support><p>Parchment</p></support><extent>170 folios 
								</extent><collation><p>
									17 quires of 10 leaves each.
									Quires are marked with catchwords on the last page of the quire and signed with Hebrew letters on the first and the last pages..
								</p></collation></supportDesc><layoutDesc><layout><p>Columns: 2;
                                                  ruled lines: 26;
                                                  written lines: 26; Uniform layout. Two columns of 26 written lines. The last four books begin in the middle of a column, after a blank space of four lines. A new pericope is either headed by the word 'parashah' or indicated by the same word in the margin. Thick parchment ruled with hard-point on the hair-side of a folio. Pricking hardly visible. </p></layout></layoutDesc></objectDesc><scriptDesc><scriptNote>Italian square script with sublinear punctuation and with accents, probably of the 14th to 15th century.</scriptNote></scriptDesc><bindingDesc><binding><p> BM/BL in-house binding.</p></binding></bindingDesc></physDesc><history><origin><origDate notBefore="1300" notAfter="1499"/><origPlace>Italy</origPlace></origin><provenance>Acquisition: The Harley Collection, formed by Robert Harley (b. 1661, d. 1724), 1st earl of Oxford and Mortimer, politician, and Edward Harley (b. 1689, d. 1741), 2nd earl of Oxford and Mortimer, book collector and patron of the arts.  Edward Harley bequeathed the library to his widow, Henrietta Cavendish, née Holles (b. 1694, d. 1755) during her lifetime and thereafter to their daughter, Margaret Cavendish Bentinck (b. 1715, d.1785), duchess of Portland; the manuscripts were sold by the Countess and the Duchess in 1753 to the nation for £10,000 (a fraction of their contemporary value) under the Act of Parliament that also established the British Museum; the Harley manuscripts form one of the foundation collections of the British Library. </provenance></history></msDesc></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><facsimile><surface n="78v" xml:id="surface-lewis-e-206-164"><graphic height="4412px" url="master/5506_0163.tif" width="3590px"/><graphic height="190px" url="thumb/5506_0163_thumb.jpg" width="154px"/><graphic height="1800px" url="web/5506_0163_web.jpg" width="1464px"/></surface></facsimile></TEI>