<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Description of Sefer Ginat egoz, with additional comments and notes of Johannes Reuchlin.</title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>cataloger</resp>
               <persName>Ilana Tahan</persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>submitter</resp>
               <persName>Agata Paluch</persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>converted to OPenn TEI format</resp>
               <orgName>Schoenberg Institute for Manuscript Studies</orgName>
            </respStmt>
            <funder>The Polonsky Foundation</funder>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The British Library</publisher>
            <availability>
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">This metadata, accompanying images, and the content of
                                        London, British Library, Oriental Manuscripts Add MS 11416: Sefer Ginat egoz, with additional comments and notes of Johannes Reuchlin. are free of known
                                        copyright restrictions and in the public domain. See the
                                        Creative Commons Zero 1.0 Universal page for usage details,
                                        https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/.</licence>
               <licence target="https://www.bl.uk/help/ethical-terms-of-use">
                                        The [British] Library respects the intellectual property
                                        rights, including moral rights, of rights holders and makes
                                        all reasonable effort to contact and consult rights owners,
                                        including, where appropriate, communities directly, or via
                                        local community organisations. Given the importance of the
                                        historical record, and the fact that that some of our
                                        digitised collections include materials that are sensitive
                                        to particular communities and groups, we ask that any use of
                                        the digitised collections is undertaken with the appropriate
                                        care. Irrespective of its copyright status, items and/or
                                        collections should not be altered or used in ways that might
                                        be derogatory to the originating individuals or communities.
                                        (Please follow the link for the complete text of the BL
                                        Ethical Terms of Use)</licence>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>Water-damaged (especially the upper margin). Slightly worm-eaten towards the gutter.</note>
            <note>
								Johannes Reuchlin: inscribed in an entry, showing that the manuscript was presented to him in 1495 by Johannes Dalburg, bishop of Worms: folio 206r.
								Otto Gereon von Gutmann of Sobernheim, archbishop of Cyrene: inscribed, 1624: folios 205r-205v; his coat of arms, folio 205v. A seal is affixed to the left-hand lower corner on folio 205r, and also on the lower margin of folio 13r.An entry on the earliest foliation of the manuscript, folio 12v.</note>
            <note type="relatedResource">
								Manuscript description based on Margoliouth, G.: Catalogue of the Hebrew and Samaritan Manuscripts in the British Museum, London 1965.
							</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <country>United Kingdom</country>
                  <settlement>London</settlement>
                  <institution>British Library</institution>
                  <repository>Oriental Manuscripts</repository>
                  <collection>Hebrew Manuscripts Digitisation
                                            Project</collection>
                  <idno type="call-number">Add MS 11416</idno>
                  <altIdentifier type="resource">
                     <idno>http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_11416</idno>
                  </altIdentifier>
                  <altIdentifier type="bl_website">
                     <idno>https://www.bl.uk/hebrew-manuscripts</idno>
                  </altIdentifier>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Sefer Ginat egoz, with additional comments and notes of Johannes Reuchlin.</summary>
                  <textLang mainLang="he">Hebrew</textLang>
                  <msItem n="1r">
                     <locus from="1r" to="206v">1r-206v</locus>
                     <title>Ginat egoz גנת אגוז</title>
                  </msItem>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc material="paper">
                        <support>
                           <p>Paper</p>
                        </support>
                        <extent>206 folios
									
								</extent>
                        <foliation>Foliated several times: in 1576 the leaves now numbered 13-205 were marked 1-192 (number 137 is repeated); in the middle of the lower margin is a later foliation in red ink; much later is the enumeration 1-206 counted backwards, on account of the Latin portions at the beginning and at the end.</foliation>
                        <collation>
                           <p>
									Quires of mostly 16 leaves each, marked by catchwords at the end (only partly preserved).
								</p>
                        </collation>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <p>Columns: 1 2;
                                                  ruled lines: 31 35;
                                                  written lines: 31 35; Uniform layout in the Hebrew section. In folios 13-205 the pages are divided into two columns.Visible hard-point and ink ruling.Initial words in larger characters.Numerous maniculae and additional notes in the margins.</p>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <scriptDesc>
                     <scriptNote>Ashkenazi semi-cursive and Latin cursive scripts of the 16th century.</scriptNote>
                  </scriptDesc>
                  <bindingDesc>
                     <binding>
                        <p> BM/BL in-house. Boxed. Spine: 'Joseph Gikatilla. Ginnath Eghoz. Hebrew. Brit. Mus. Additional Ms. 11416.'</p>
                     </binding>
                  </bindingDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="1400" notAfter="1599"/>
                     <origPlace>Italy</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>Acquisition: Purchased by the British Museum at Evans' sale, lot 1134, on 26 July 1838: inscribed, folio [210v].</provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <facsimile>
      <surface n="78v" xml:id="surface-lewis-e-206-164">
         <graphic height="4412px" url="master/5506_0163.tif" width="3590px"/>
         <graphic height="190px" url="thumb/5506_0163_thumb.jpg" width="154px"/>
         <graphic height="1800px" url="web/5506_0163_web.jpg" width="1464px"/>
      </surface>
   </facsimile>
</TEI>
