<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Description of Maḥzor(מחזור)</title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>cataloger</resp>
               <persName>Ilana Tahan</persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>submitter</resp>
               <persName>Agata Paluch</persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>converted to OPenn TEI format</resp>
               <orgName>Schoenberg Institute for Manuscript Studies</orgName>
            </respStmt>
            <funder>The Polonsky Foundation</funder>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The British Library</publisher>
            <availability>
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">This metadata, accompanying images, and the content of
                                        London, British Library, Oriental Manuscripts Harley MS 5583: Maḥzor are free of known
                                        copyright restrictions and in the public domain. See the
                                        Creative Commons Zero 1.0 Universal page for usage details,
                                        https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/.</licence>
               <licence target="https://www.bl.uk/help/ethical-terms-of-use">
                                        The [British] Library respects the intellectual property
                                        rights, including moral rights, of rights holders and makes
                                        all reasonable effort to contact and consult rights owners,
                                        including, where appropriate, communities directly, or via
                                        local community organisations. Given the importance of the
                                        historical record, and the fact that that some of our
                                        digitised collections include materials that are sensitive
                                        to particular communities and groups, we ask that any use of
                                        the digitised collections is undertaken with the appropriate
                                        care. Irrespective of its copyright status, items and/or
                                        collections should not be altered or used in ways that might
                                        be derogatory to the originating individuals or communities.
                                        (Please follow the link for the complete text of the BL
                                        Ethical Terms of Use)</licence>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>Several leaves cancelled (e.g. after folio 203 and 218). Defective at the beginning. A lacuna after folio 178.</note>
            <note>
								Yeshaʿyah ben Avraham Kohen and perhaps the patron of this manuscript: inscribed in a note: folio 125r, 247r and 253v.
								Mosheh Aboab: inscribed, folio 191r and 253r.
								Bernard Mould (b. c. 1683; d. 1744), chaplain at Smyrna: inscribed with his name, Smyrna, 1724 (folio 2r); sold to Edward Harley on 28 July 1725 (see , ). An English description of the manuscript by Bernard Mould: stuck to folio 1v.Inscription by Harley's librarian, Humfrey Wanley, 28 Julij A.D. 1725 (folio 2r).</note>
            <note type="relatedResource">
								Manuscript description based on Margoliouth, G.: Catalogue of the Hebrew and Samaritan Manuscripts in the British Museum, London 1965.
							</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <country>United Kingdom</country>
                  <settlement>London</settlement>
                  <institution>British Library</institution>
                  <repository>Oriental Manuscripts</repository>
                  <collection>Hebrew Manuscripts Digitisation
                                            Project</collection>
                  <idno type="call-number">Harley MS 5583</idno>
                  <altIdentifier type="resource">
                     <idno>http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Harley_MS_5583</idno>
                  </altIdentifier>
                  <altIdentifier type="bl_website">
                     <idno>https://www.bl.uk/hebrew-manuscripts</idno>
                  </altIdentifier>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>A daily prayer book for festivals and fasts according to the Romanian rite.</summary>
                  <textLang mainLang="he">Hebrew</textLang>
                  <msItem n="1r">
                     <locus from="1r" to="313v">1r-313v</locus>
                     <title>Maḥzor מחזור</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="2r">
                     <locus from="2r" to="113v">2r-113v</locus>
                     <title>Services for Pesaḥ</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="113v">
                     <locus from="113v" to="179v">113v-179v</locus>
                     <title>Services for Shavu῾ot</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="179v">
                     <locus from="179v" to="191v">179v-191v</locus>
                     <title>Poetical pieces for the special Sabbaths</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="191v">
                     <locus from="191v" to="300r">191v-300r</locus>
                     <title>Services for fasts and other occasions</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="300v">
                     <locus from="300v" to="313v">300v-313v</locus>
                     <title>Ḳinot</title>
                  </msItem>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc material="parchment">
                        <support>
                           <p>Parchment</p>
                        </support>
                        <extent>313 folios 
									
								</extent>
                        <collation>
                           <p>
									Quires of mostly 8 leaves each, partly marked with catchwords at the end.
								</p>
                        </collation>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <p>Columns: 1;
                                                  ruled lines: 24;
                                                  written lines: 24; Uniform layout.Visible pricking and hard-point ruling.Hair side and flesh side of the folios distinguishable.Initial words written in larger characters. Catchwords on every verso from folio 179 on, only partly preserved.</p>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <scriptDesc>
                     <scriptNote>Sefardi square script of the 14th to 15th century, punctuated. Missing parts of the original completed in a Sefardi semi-cursive script of the 15th century (e.g. folios 113-123, 179-190, 274-313). Mosheh?: the name Mosheh is marked off in the initial lines on folio 147r.</scriptNote>
                  </scriptDesc>
                  <bindingDesc>
                     <binding>
                        <p> Post-1600. Red leather Harleian binding, gold-tooled. Spine: 'Mahzor for Festivals and Fasts Rite of Romania. Brit. Mus. Harley MS. 5583.'</p>
                     </binding>
                  </bindingDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="1300" notAfter="1399"/>
                     <origPlace>Ottoman Empire</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>Acquisition: The Harley Collection, formed by Robert Harley (b. 1661, d. 1724), 1st earl of Oxford and Mortimer, politician, and Edward Harley (b. 1689, d. 1741), 2nd earl of Oxford and Mortimer, book collector and patron of the arts.
Edward Harley bequeathed the library to his widow, Henrietta Cavendish, née Holles (b. 1694, d. 1755) during her lifetime and thereafter to their daughter, Margaret Cavendish Bentinck (b. 1715, d.1785), duchess of Portland; the manuscripts were sold by the Countess and the Duchess in 1753 to the nation for £10,000 (a fraction of their contemporary value) under the Act of Parliament that also established the British Museum; the Harley manuscripts form one of the foundation collections of the British Library.</provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <facsimile>
      <surface n="78v" xml:id="surface-lewis-e-206-164">
         <graphic height="4412px" url="master/5506_0163.tif" width="3590px"/>
         <graphic height="190px" url="thumb/5506_0163_thumb.jpg" width="154px"/>
         <graphic height="1800px" url="web/5506_0163_web.jpg" width="1464px"/>
      </surface>
   </facsimile>
</TEI>
