<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><teiHeader><fileDesc><titleStmt><title>Description of Medical work. </title><respStmt><resp>cataloger</resp><persName>Ilana Tahan</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>submitter</resp><persName>Agata Paluch</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>converted to OPenn TEI format</resp><orgName>Schoenberg Institute for Manuscript Studies</orgName></respStmt><funder>The Polonsky Foundation</funder></titleStmt><publicationStmt><publisher>The British Library</publisher><availability><licence target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">This metadata, accompanying images, and the content of
                                        London, British Library, Oriental Manuscripts Add MS 15455: Medical work.  are free of known
                                        copyright restrictions and in the public domain. See the
                                        Creative Commons Zero 1.0 Universal page for usage details,
                                        https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/.</licence><licence target="https://www.bl.uk/help/ethical-terms-of-use">
                                        The [British] Library respects the intellectual property
                                        rights, including moral rights, of rights holders and makes
                                        all reasonable effort to contact and consult rights owners,
                                        including, where appropriate, communities directly, or via
                                        local community organisations. Given the importance of the
                                        historical record, and the fact that that some of our
                                        digitised collections include materials that are sensitive
                                        to particular communities and groups, we ask that any use of
                                        the digitised collections is undertaken with the appropriate
                                        care. Irrespective of its copyright status, items and/or
                                        collections should not be altered or used in ways that might
                                        be derogatory to the originating individuals or communities.
                                        (Please follow the link for the complete text of the BL
                                        Ethical Terms of Use)</licence></availability></publicationStmt><notesStmt><note>Losses to damp and mould in parchment and paper, infilled before rebinding.  Tidemarks and mould spotting.  Paling ink. </note><note>Folios 1-4 are parchment leaves of the 12th century, containing a portion of Homily IV of St. Chrysostom on Isaiah 6:1. Folio 5 is a paper flyleaf of the 17th to 18th century (partly folded), and contains a short piece in Hebrew dealing with the plague, followed by two pieces in Turkish (in Hebrew characters) on the same subject. Folios 6-8: notes and scribblings, partly illegible. Shelomoh Martin, perhaps a former owner, mentioned in two entries in connection with money transactions. Folios 1v-3v and 6r-8v, margins: a Hebrew-Turkish vocabulary, apparently of the 17th century. </note><note type="relatedResource">
                        
                        
                        
                        Manuscript description based on Margoliouth, G.: Catalogue of the Hebrew and Samaritan Manuscripts in the British Museum, London 1965.
                     
                     
                     
                     </note></notesStmt><sourceDesc><msDesc><msIdentifier><country>United Kingdom</country><settlement>London</settlement><institution>British Library</institution><repository>Oriental Manuscripts</repository><collection>Hebrew Manuscripts Digitisation
                                            Project</collection><idno type="call-number">Add MS 15455</idno><altIdentifier type="resource"><idno>http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_15455</idno></altIdentifier><altIdentifier type="bl_website"><idno>https://www.bl.uk/hebrew-manuscripts</idno></altIdentifier></msIdentifier><msContents><summary>Medical work. </summary><textLang mainLang="he"/><msItem n="1r"><locus from="1r" to="210v">1r-210v</locus><title>Shushan ha-refu᾿ah שושן הרפואה</title></msItem></msContents><physDesc><objectDesc><supportDesc material="mixed"><support><p>Mixed</p></support><extent>210 folios
                           
                           
                           
                           
                        
                        
                        
                        </extent><collation><p>
                           
                           
                           
                           21 quires of originally 10, 8 and 12 leaves each, with parchment used for the two outer and the two inner leaves of a quire in the earlier part, and for the outer leaves only in the latter part. 
                        
                        
                        
                        </p></collation></supportDesc><layoutDesc><layout><p>Columns: 1;
                                                  ruled lines: 31;
                                                  written lines: 31; Uniform layout. Hard-point ruling visible. Hair side and flesh side of parchment folios distinguishable. Large square initial words. Additions and notes on margin largely by the main scribe. Maniculae, e.g. folios 152v-153v, 155r, 156v, 157r. </p></layout></layoutDesc></objectDesc><scriptDesc><scriptNote>Byzantine semi-cursive scripts of the 15th century. </scriptNote></scriptDesc><bindingDesc><binding><p> BM in-house.  Spine: 'Shushan ha-Re'Phu'ah. Jekuthiel Ben Solomon's Versions of Lilium Medicinae. Hebrew. Brit. Mus. Additional 15,455.'</p></binding></bindingDesc></physDesc><history><origin><origDate notBefore="1400" notAfter="1499"/></origin><provenance>Jeuda Bensaltiel of Co[n]stantina</provenance><provenance>Segnor Hakham Kohen</provenance><provenance>Acquisition: Purchased by the British Museum through Adolphus Asher(b. 1800, d. 1853), Berlin bookseller and dealer to the British Museum 1841-1853, on 08 March 1845: inscribed, folio 210v. </provenance></history></msDesc></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><facsimile><surface n="78v" xml:id="surface-lewis-e-206-164"><graphic height="4412px" url="master/5506_0163.tif" width="3590px"/><graphic height="190px" url="thumb/5506_0163_thumb.jpg" width="154px"/><graphic height="1800px" url="web/5506_0163_web.jpg" width="1464px"/></surface></facsimile></TEI>