<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Description of Hebrew Bible, volume 1: Pentateuch</title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>cataloger</resp>
               <persName>Ilana Tahan</persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>submitter</resp>
               <persName>Agata Paluch</persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>converted to OPenn TEI format</resp>
               <orgName>Schoenberg Institute for Manuscript Studies</orgName>
            </respStmt>
            <funder>The Polonsky Foundation</funder>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The British Library</publisher>
            <availability>
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">This metadata, accompanying images, and the content of
                                        London, British Library, Oriental Manuscripts Harley MS 5498a: Hebrew Bible, volume 1: Pentateuch are free of known
                                        copyright restrictions and in the public domain. See the
                                        Creative Commons Zero 1.0 Universal page for usage details,
                                        https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/.</licence>
               <licence target="https://www.bl.uk/help/ethical-terms-of-use">
                                        The [British] Library respects the intellectual property
                                        rights, including moral rights, of rights holders and makes
                                        all reasonable effort to contact and consult rights owners,
                                        including, where appropriate, communities directly, or via
                                        local community organisations. Given the importance of the
                                        historical record, and the fact that that some of our
                                        digitised collections include materials that are sensitive
                                        to particular communities and groups, we ask that any use of
                                        the digitised collections is undertaken with the appropriate
                                        care. Irrespective of its copyright status, items and/or
                                        collections should not be altered or used in ways that might
                                        be derogatory to the originating individuals or communities.
                                        (Please follow the link for the complete text of the BL
                                        Ethical Terms of Use)</licence>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>The codex has been trimmed and it became smaller in size than the other three volumes.</note>
            <note/>
            <note type="relatedResource">
                        
                        
                        
                        Manuscript description based on Margoliouth, G.: Catalogue of the Hebrew and Samaritan Manuscripts in the British Museum, London 1965.
                     
                     
                     
                     </note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <country>United Kingdom</country>
                  <settlement>London</settlement>
                  <institution>British Library</institution>
                  <repository>Oriental Manuscripts</repository>
                  <collection>Hebrew Manuscripts Digitisation
                                            Project</collection>
                  <idno type="call-number">Harley MS 5498a</idno>
                  <altIdentifier type="resource">
                     <idno>http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Harley_MS_5498a</idno>
                  </altIdentifier>
                  <altIdentifier type="bl_website">
                     <idno>https://www.bl.uk/hebrew-manuscripts</idno>
                  </altIdentifier>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Hebrew Bible, volume 1: Pentateuch</summary>
                  <textLang mainLang="he">Hebrew</textLang>
                  <msItem n="1r">
                     <locus from="1r" to="124r">1r-124r</locus>
                     <title>Torah  תורה</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="2v">
                     <locus from="2v" to="30v">2v-30v</locus>
                     <title>Genesis</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="30v">
                     <locus from="30v" to="53v">30v-53v</locus>
                     <title>Exodus</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="53v">
                     <locus from="53v" to="72r">53v-72r</locus>
                     <title>Leviticus</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="72r">
                     <locus from="72r" to="100r">72r-100r</locus>
                     <title>Numbers</title>
                  </msItem>
                  <msItem n="100r">
                     <locus from="100r" to="124v">100r-124v</locus>
                     <title>Deuteronomy</title>
                  </msItem>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc material="parchment">
                        <support>
                           <p>Parchment</p>
                        </support>
                        <extent>124 folios (+4 unfoliated flyleaves at the beginning and at the end).
                           
                           
                           
                           
                        
                        
                        
                        </extent>
                        <collation>
                           <p>
                           
                           
                           
                           10 quires (catchwords, signatures have been trimmed off). Quires are of 12 leaves each,Several unfoliated paper flyleaves (of Christian provenance, with watermark of two lions holding a banner) at the beginning and at the end.
                        
                        
                        
                        </p>
                        </collation>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <p>Columns: 2;
                                                  ruled lines: 32;
                                                  written lines: 32; Uniform layout. Leviticus and Deuteronomy begin a new column.Initial word at the beginning of Numbers is unfinished.Weekly pericopes in volume 1 marked by pen-decorated פרש' in the margin at the beginning, later on only by non-decorative פר'. The masoretic rubric giving the number of verses etc. has only been given after Genesis.</p>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <scriptDesc>
                     <scriptNote>Sefardi square script, punctuated through the main text and unpunctuated through the masoretic notes, of the 14th century.</scriptNote>
                  </scriptDesc>
                  <decoDesc>
                     <decoNote type="other">Several pen-decorated signs, indicating the beginning of the pericope. Several pen-decorated inital and middle-letters, especially ל of the uppermost line of the text. Masorah in micrographical form. 
                     
                     
                     
                     </decoNote>
                  </decoDesc>
                  <bindingDesc>
                     <binding>
                        <p> Post-1600 Harleian binding, red leather with gold tooling, marble paper pastedown.  Spine: 'Bible I. Hebrew. Brit. Mus. Harl. Ms. 5498.'</p>
                     </binding>
                  </bindingDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="1300" notAfter="1399"/>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>Acquisition: Inscription by Edward Harley's librarian, Humfrey Wanley, 28 July 1725 (folio 2r of volume 1). The Harley Collection, formed by Robert Harley (b. 1661, d. 1724), 1st earl of Oxford and Mortimer, politician, and Edward Harley (b. 1689, d. 1741), 2nd earl of Oxford and Mortimer, book collector and patron of the arts. Edward Harley bequeathed the library to his widow, Henrietta, née Cavendish Holles (b. 1694, d. 1755) during her lifetime and thereafter to their daughter, Margaret Cavendish Bentinck (b. 1715, d.1785), duchess of Portland; the manuscripts were sold by the Countess and the Duchess in 1753 to the nation for £10,000 (a fraction of their contemporary value) under the Act of Parliament that also established the British Museum; the Harley manuscripts form one of the foundation collections of the British Library. </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <facsimile>
      <surface n="78v" xml:id="surface-lewis-e-206-164">
         <graphic height="4412px" url="master/5506_0163.tif" width="3590px"/>
         <graphic height="190px" url="thumb/5506_0163_thumb.jpg" width="154px"/>
         <graphic height="1800px" url="web/5506_0163_web.jpg" width="1464px"/>
      </surface>
   </facsimile>
</TEI>
