<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><teiHeader><fileDesc><titleStmt><title>Description of Mishneh Torah (משנה תורה)</title><respStmt><resp>cataloger</resp><persName>Ilana Tahan</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>submitter</resp><persName>Agata Paluch</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>converted to OPenn TEI format</resp><orgName>Schoenberg Institute for Manuscript Studies</orgName></respStmt><funder>The Polonsky Foundation</funder></titleStmt><publicationStmt><publisher>The British Library</publisher><availability><licence target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">This metadata, accompanying images, and the content of
                                        London, British Library, Oriental Manuscripts Harley MS 5702: Mishneh Torah  are free of known
                                        copyright restrictions and in the public domain. See the
                                        Creative Commons Zero 1.0 Universal page for usage details,
                                        https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/.</licence><licence target="https://www.bl.uk/help/ethical-terms-of-use">
                                        The [British] Library respects the intellectual property
                                        rights, including moral rights, of rights holders and makes
                                        all reasonable effort to contact and consult rights owners,
                                        including, where appropriate, communities directly, or via
                                        local community organisations. Given the importance of the
                                        historical record, and the fact that that some of our
                                        digitised collections include materials that are sensitive
                                        to particular communities and groups, we ask that any use of
                                        the digitised collections is undertaken with the appropriate
                                        care. Irrespective of its copyright status, items and/or
                                        collections should not be altered or used in ways that might
                                        be derogatory to the originating individuals or communities.
                                        (Please follow the link for the complete text of the BL
                                        Ethical Terms of Use)</licence></availability></publicationStmt><notesStmt><note>Stained.  Margins slightly damaged. </note><note>Short notes in a 14th or 15th century Ashkenazi hand: folio 198v (only upper part of leaf is preserved, otherwise blank). A small octavo paper leaf with notes:  folio199. Folio 200: a small leaf containing some Ashkenazi notes on one side, which mention a certain rabi Bendit and his father Gershon. </note><note type="relatedResource">
								Manuscript description based on Margoliouth, G.: Catalogue of the Hebrew and Samaritan Manuscripts in the British Museum, London 1965.
							</note></notesStmt><sourceDesc><msDesc><msIdentifier><country>United Kingdom</country><settlement>London</settlement><institution>British Library</institution><repository>Oriental Manuscripts</repository><collection>Hebrew Manuscripts Digitisation
                                            Project</collection><idno type="call-number">Harley MS 5702</idno><altIdentifier type="resource"><idno>http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Harley_MS_5702</idno></altIdentifier><altIdentifier type="bl_website"><idno>https://www.bl.uk/hebrew-manuscripts</idno></altIdentifier></msIdentifier><msContents><summary>Books IV-VI of Maimonides' Mishneh Torah, with glosses in the style of the Tosafists, followed by Meir of Rothenburg's responses on the subject of the same books. </summary><textLang mainLang="he"/><msItem n="1r"><locus from="1r" to="200v">1r-200v</locus><title>Mishneh Torah  משנה תורה</title></msItem><msItem n="2v"><locus from="2v" to="12r">2v-12r</locus><title>Table of contents </title></msItem><msItem n="12v"><locus from="12v" to="78r">12v-78r</locus><title>Sefer nashim </title></msItem><msItem n="78r"><locus from="78r" to="142v">78r-142v</locus><title>Sefer ḳedushah</title></msItem><msItem n="142v"><locus from="142v" to="177r">142v-177r</locus><title>Sefer hafla᾿ah</title></msItem><msItem n="177r"><locus from="177r" to="190v">177r-190v</locus><title>Teshuvot le-sefer nashim</title></msItem><msItem n="190v"><locus from="190v" to="194v">190v-194v</locus><title>Teshuvot le-sefer ḳedushah</title></msItem><msItem n="194v"><locus from="194v" to="200v">194v-200v</locus><title>Teshuvot le-sefer hafla᾿ah</title></msItem></msContents><physDesc><objectDesc><supportDesc material="parchment"><support><p>Parchment</p></support><extent>200 folios 
									
								</extent><collation><p>
									Quires of 8 leaves each (the last quires is missing one leaf). 
									There are catchwords at the end of the quires. 
								</p></collation></supportDesc><layoutDesc><layout><p>Columns: 1 2;
                                                  ruled lines: 41 59;
                                                  written lines: 41 59; In folio 2v-12r, 179r-199v each page is divided into 2 columns, with 50-59 lines in a full column. The pages contained in folios 12v-178v, which are undivided, have 41 or 42 lines each. Pricking and plummet ruling (each bifolio on both sides) is visible. Hair-side and flesh-side of folios indistinguishable. Chapter numbers given in larger characters. The main text is given in larger characters and the comments are in smaller characters. Occasional marginal notes and additions. </p></layout></layoutDesc></objectDesc><scriptDesc><scriptNote>Ashkenazi semi-cursive script of the 14th century. </scriptNote></scriptDesc><bindingDesc><binding><p> BM in-house. Harley coat of arms on the upper and lower covers.  Spine title: 'Maimonides. Mishneh Thorah. Books IV &amp; VI. Hebrew. Brit. Mus. Harl. Or. 5702.'</p></binding></bindingDesc></physDesc><history><origin><origDate notBefore="1300" notAfter="1399"/><origPlace>Germany</origPlace></origin><provenance>Acquisition: The Harley Collection, formed by Robert Harley (b. 1661, d. 1724), 1st earl of Oxford and Mortimer, politician, and Edward Harley (b. 1689, d. 1741), 2nd earl of Oxford and Mortimer, book collector and patron of the arts.
Edward Harley bequeathed the library to his widow, Henrietta Cavendish, née Holles (b. 1694, d. 1755) during her lifetime and thereafter to their daughter, Margaret Cavendish Bentinck (b. 1715, d.1785), duchess of Portland; the manuscripts were sold by the Countess and the Duchess in 1753 to the nation for £10,000 (a fraction of their contemporary value) under the Act of Parliament that also established the British Museum; the Harley manuscripts form one of the foundation collections of the British Library.</provenance></history></msDesc></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><facsimile><surface n="78v" xml:id="surface-lewis-e-206-164"><graphic height="4412px" url="master/5506_0163.tif" width="3590px"/><graphic height="190px" url="thumb/5506_0163_thumb.jpg" width="154px"/><graphic height="1800px" url="web/5506_0163_web.jpg" width="1464px"/></surface></facsimile></TEI>