<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Description of The Psalms, with vowel-points and accents, masorah magna and parva.</title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>cataloger</resp>
               <persName>Ilana Tahan</persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>submitter</resp>
               <persName>Agata Paluch</persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>converted to OPenn TEI format</resp>
               <orgName>Schoenberg Institute for Manuscript Studies</orgName>
            </respStmt>
            <funder>The Polonsky Foundation</funder>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The British Library</publisher>
            <availability>
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">This metadata, accompanying images, and the content of
                                        London, British Library, Oriental Manuscripts Add MS 18830: The Psalms, with vowel-points and accents, masorah magna and parva. are free of known
                                        copyright restrictions and in the public domain. See the
                                        Creative Commons Zero 1.0 Universal page for usage details,
                                        https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/.</licence>
               <licence target="https://www.bl.uk/help/ethical-terms-of-use">
                                        The [British] Library respects the intellectual property
                                        rights, including moral rights, of rights holders and makes
                                        all reasonable effort to contact and consult rights owners,
                                        including, where appropriate, communities directly, or via
                                        local community organisations. Given the importance of the
                                        historical record, and the fact that that some of our
                                        digitised collections include materials that are sensitive
                                        to particular communities and groups, we ask that any use of
                                        the digitised collections is undertaken with the appropriate
                                        care. Irrespective of its copyright status, items and/or
                                        collections should not be altered or used in ways that might
                                        be derogatory to the originating individuals or communities.
                                        (Please follow the link for the complete text of the BL
                                        Ethical Terms of Use)</licence>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>Folio 120v: Psalterium istud est Monasterii Sancti Benedicti. Monastery of Sancta Maria de angelis in Florence and of Sanct Benedict outside the walls in Florence, inscribed as owners of this psaltery in several Latin notes on folios 1v, 3r, 120v. Folio 121v, records of birth, with a date of 5422 (1662).</note>
            <note type="relatedResource">
								Manuscript description based on Margoliouth, G.: Catalogue of the Hebrew and Samaritan Manuscripts in the British Museum, London 1965.
							</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <country>United Kingdom</country>
                  <settlement>London</settlement>
                  <institution>British Library</institution>
                  <repository>Oriental Manuscripts</repository>
                  <collection>Hebrew Manuscripts Digitisation
                                            Project</collection>
                  <idno type="call-number">Add MS 18830</idno>
                  <altIdentifier type="resource">
                     <idno>http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_18830</idno>
                  </altIdentifier>
                  <altIdentifier type="bl_website">
                     <idno>https://www.bl.uk/hebrew-manuscripts</idno>
                  </altIdentifier>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>The Psalms, with vowel-points and accents, masorah magna and parva.</summary>
                  <textLang mainLang="he">Hebrew</textLang>
                  <msItem n="1r">
                     <locus from="1r" to="122v">1r-122v</locus>
                     <title>Tehilim תהילים </title>
                  </msItem>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc material="parchment">
                        <support>
                           <p>Parchment</p>
                        </support>
                        <extent>122 folios
									
								</extent>
                        <collation>
                           <p>
									Quires of mostly 6 leaves each. 
									Catchwords trimmed away.
								</p>
                        </collation>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <p>Columns: 2;
                                                  ruled lines: 11;
                                                  written lines: 11; Uniform layout. The Latin beginnings of the Psalms marked in the margins.Masorah magna occupies 1 line in the upper margin and up to 2 lines in the lower margin, sometimes written in an ornamental pattern.Visible pricking and folio by folio ruling with a hard-point. Hair side and flesh side of folios distinguishable. </p>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <scriptDesc>
                     <scriptNote>Fine Sefardi square script, punctuated, of the 14th century.</scriptNote>
                  </scriptDesc>
                  <bindingDesc>
                     <binding>
                        <p> BL in-house.  Spine: 'Psalterium. Hebrew. British Library. Additional 18830.'</p>
                     </binding>
                  </bindingDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="1300" notAfter="1399"/>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>Acquisition: Löwy, Albert (Abraham) (b. 1816, d. 1908), Hebrew scholar and minister in the West London Synagogue of British Jews: purchased by the British Library from him on 10 January 1852: inscribed on folio [123v]. </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <facsimile>
      <surface n="78v" xml:id="surface-lewis-e-206-164">
         <graphic height="4412px" url="master/5506_0163.tif" width="3590px"/>
         <graphic height="190px" url="thumb/5506_0163_thumb.jpg" width="154px"/>
         <graphic height="1800px" url="web/5506_0163_web.jpg" width="1464px"/>
      </surface>
   </facsimile>
</TEI>
