<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><teiHeader><fileDesc><titleStmt><title>Description of Sefer ha-ḥinukh, a commentary on the 613 precepts arranged in the order of the weekly parashiyot.</title><respStmt><resp>cataloger</resp><persName>Ilana Tahan</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>submitter</resp><persName>Agata Paluch</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>converted to OPenn TEI format</resp><orgName>Schoenberg Institute for Manuscript Studies</orgName></respStmt><funder>The Polonsky Foundation</funder></titleStmt><publicationStmt><publisher>The British Library</publisher><availability><licence target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">This metadata, accompanying images, and the content of
                                        London, British Library, Oriental Manuscripts Or 2855: Sefer ha-ḥinukh, a commentary on the 613 precepts arranged in the order of the weekly parashiyot. are free of known
                                        copyright restrictions and in the public domain. See the
                                        Creative Commons Zero 1.0 Universal page for usage details,
                                        https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/.</licence><licence target="https://www.bl.uk/help/ethical-terms-of-use">
                                        The [British] Library respects the intellectual property
                                        rights, including moral rights, of rights holders and makes
                                        all reasonable effort to contact and consult rights owners,
                                        including, where appropriate, communities directly, or via
                                        local community organisations. Given the importance of the
                                        historical record, and the fact that that some of our
                                        digitised collections include materials that are sensitive
                                        to particular communities and groups, we ask that any use of
                                        the digitised collections is undertaken with the appropriate
                                        care. Irrespective of its copyright status, items and/or
                                        collections should not be altered or used in ways that might
                                        be derogatory to the originating individuals or communities.
                                        (Please follow the link for the complete text of the BL
                                        Ethical Terms of Use)</licence></availability></publicationStmt><notesStmt><note>Folio 290 is only partly preserved.</note><note>
								Shemu᾿el ha-Rofe: inscribed in the colophon, folio 2r.
								Mordekhai, Rafa᾿el ben Mosheh ha-Melamed and Mosheh ben Benyamin of Bologne: inscribed in the contract of sale, folio 1r.</note><note type="relatedResource">
								Manuscript description based on Margoliouth, G.: Catalogue of the Hebrew and Samaritan Manuscripts in the British Museum, London 1965.
							</note></notesStmt><sourceDesc><msDesc><msIdentifier><country>United Kingdom</country><settlement>London</settlement><institution>British Library</institution><repository>Oriental Manuscripts</repository><collection>Hebrew Manuscripts Digitisation
                                            Project</collection><idno type="call-number">Or 2855</idno><altIdentifier type="resource"><idno>http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Or_2855</idno></altIdentifier><altIdentifier type="bl_website"><idno>https://www.bl.uk/hebrew-manuscripts</idno></altIdentifier></msIdentifier><msContents><summary>Sefer ha-ḥinukh, a commentary on the 613 precepts arranged in the order of the weekly parashiyot.</summary><textLang mainLang="he"/><msItem n="1r"><locus from="1r" to="289v">1r-289v</locus><title>Sefer ha-ḥinukh ספר החינוך</title></msItem></msContents><physDesc><objectDesc><supportDesc material="parchment"><support><p>Parchment</p></support><extent>290 folios 
									
								</extent><collation><p>
									30 quires of mostly 10 leaves each, marked with catchwords  and Hebrew letters at the end.
									Quires no. 12, 21, 22, 25 have 8 leaves each, quire no. 30 has 6 leaves only.
								</p></collation></supportDesc><layoutDesc><layout><p>Columns: 1 ;
                                                  ruled lines: 34;
                                                  written lines: 34; Uniform layout. Visible pricking and hard-point ruling (bifolium by bifolium).Hair-side and flesh-side of the folios distinguishable, with visible scratching.Last line written outside the ruling.Occasional infralinear vocalization.Chapter numbers in the margins, within pen and ink simple design.</p></layout></layoutDesc></objectDesc><scriptDesc><scriptNote>Italian semi-cursive script of the 14th century. Avraham (?), the scribe: his name marked off within the text.</scriptNote></scriptDesc><bindingDesc><binding><p> BM in-house. Spine title: 'Sefer Ha Chinnuk. Hebrew. Brit. Mus. Oriental 2855.'</p></binding></bindingDesc></physDesc><history><origin><origDate notBefore="1350" notAfter="1399"/><origPlace>Italy</origPlace></origin><provenance>Acquisition: 
								N. Rabinowitz: bought from him by the British Museum on 18 April 1885 (folio [290v]).</provenance></history></msDesc></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><facsimile><surface n="78v" xml:id="surface-lewis-e-206-164"><graphic height="4412px" url="master/5506_0163.tif" width="3590px"/><graphic height="190px" url="thumb/5506_0163_thumb.jpg" width="154px"/><graphic height="1800px" url="web/5506_0163_web.jpg" width="1464px"/></surface></facsimile></TEI>