<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><teiHeader><fileDesc><titleStmt><title>Description of Even ha-῾ezer and Hoshen mishpaṭ of Arba῾ah Turim of Jacob ben Asher; Hilkhot de῾ot of the Mishneh Torah of Maimonides. </title><respStmt><resp>cataloger</resp><persName>Ilana Tahan</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>submitter</resp><persName>Agata Paluch</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>converted to OPenn TEI format</resp><orgName>Schoenberg Institute for Manuscript Studies</orgName></respStmt><funder>The Polonsky Foundation</funder></titleStmt><publicationStmt><publisher>The British Library</publisher><availability><licence target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">This metadata, accompanying images, and the content of
                                        London, British Library, Oriental Manuscripts Harley MS 5717: Even ha-῾ezer and Hoshen mishpaṭ of Arba῾ah Turim of Jacob ben Asher; Hilkhot de῾ot of the Mishneh Torah of Maimonides.  are free of known
                                        copyright restrictions and in the public domain. See the
                                        Creative Commons Zero 1.0 Universal page for usage details,
                                        https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/.</licence><licence target="https://www.bl.uk/help/ethical-terms-of-use">
                                        The [British] Library respects the intellectual property
                                        rights, including moral rights, of rights holders and makes
                                        all reasonable effort to contact and consult rights owners,
                                        including, where appropriate, communities directly, or via
                                        local community organisations. Given the importance of the
                                        historical record, and the fact that that some of our
                                        digitised collections include materials that are sensitive
                                        to particular communities and groups, we ask that any use of
                                        the digitised collections is undertaken with the appropriate
                                        care. Irrespective of its copyright status, items and/or
                                        collections should not be altered or used in ways that might
                                        be derogatory to the originating individuals or communities.
                                        (Please follow the link for the complete text of the BL
                                        Ethical Terms of Use)</licence></availability></publicationStmt><notesStmt><note>
								[5]235, that is, 1475: date of production added by a later hand, probably by Shimshon Cohen Modon (folio 265v).

								Luigi da Bologna, a converted Jew working for the Inquisition as censor (active at the end of the sixteenth, beginning of seventeenth century): inscribed with his name as censor, 1598 (folio 265r); see 104, and appendix § 112-117.
Frater Giovanni Montifal. di Modena: inscribed with his name, undated (folio 265r); see , appendix § 88.

								Hippolite of Ferrara, Franciscan censor (active at the end of the 16th century-beginning of 17th century, in Cremona?): inscribed with his name, 1603 (folio 265r); see , appendix § 18-19, 93.

								Giovanni Domenico Vistorini: inscribed with his name, 1610 (folio 265r); see , appendix § 85-87.

								Shimshon Cohen Modon, the younger: inscribed with his name in an ownership's note (folio 1r).</note><note type="relatedResource">
								Manuscript description based on Margoliouth, G.: Catalogue of the Hebrew and Samaritan Manuscripts in the British Museum, London 1965.
							</note></notesStmt><sourceDesc><msDesc><msIdentifier><country>United Kingdom</country><settlement>London</settlement><institution>British Library</institution><repository>Oriental Manuscripts</repository><collection>Hebrew Manuscripts Digitisation
                                            Project</collection><idno type="call-number">Harley MS 5717</idno><altIdentifier type="resource"><idno>http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Harley_MS_5717</idno></altIdentifier><altIdentifier type="bl_website"><idno>https://www.bl.uk/hebrew-manuscripts</idno></altIdentifier></msIdentifier><msContents><summary>Even ha-῾ezer and Hoshen mishpaṭ of Arba῾ah Turim of Jacob ben Asher; Hilkhot de῾ot of the Mishneh Torah of Maimonides. </summary><textLang mainLang="he"/><msItem n="2r"><locus from="2r" to="261v">2r-261v</locus><title>Arba'ah Ṭurim ארבעה טורים</title></msItem><msItem n="261v"><locus from="261v" to="265v">261v-265v</locus><title>Hilkhot de῾ot הלכות דעות</title></msItem></msContents><physDesc><objectDesc><supportDesc material="parchment"><support><p>Parchment</p></support><extent>266 folios 
									
								</extent><collation><p>
									27 quires: i-vii10 (folios 2-71), viii-ix8 (folios 72-87), x12 (folios 88-99), xi8 (folios 100-107), xii12 (folios 108-119), xiii8 (folios 120-127), xiv12 (folios 128-139), xv8 (folios 140-147), xvi12 (folios 148-159), xvii8 (folios 160-167), xviii12 (folios 168-179), xix-xx8 (folios 180-195), xxi12 (folios 196-207), xxii8 (folios 208-215), xxiii12 (folios 216-227), xxiv8 (folios 228-235), xxv12 (folios 236-247), xxvi8 (folios 248-255), xxviieleven (folios 256-266).
								</p></collation></supportDesc><layoutDesc><layout><p>Columns: 2;
                                                  ruled lines: 37;
                                                  written lines: 37; Uniform layout. Visible pricking and horizontal ruling in ink, page by page, and vertical ruling with plummet, also page by page. Hair side and flesh side of the folios distinguishable.Last line written outside ruling.Initial words in larger semi-cursive script. Horizontal decorated leaf catchwords.Censors’ erasures (e.g., folios 14r, 94v, 171r, 216v, 243r, 252v).</p></layout></layoutDesc></objectDesc><scriptDesc><scriptNote>Sefardi semi-cursive script, unpunctuated. Hayim Barbut: inscribed with his name in the colophon (folio 265v). Decorated by Florentine artists.</scriptNote></scriptDesc><decoDesc><decoNote type="initial"><locus>2r</locus>2 decorated initial-word panels accompanied with a full floral border inhabited by birds, puttos and decorated with medallions containing figures and a coat of arms, in colours and gold.  
							</decoNote><decoNote type="initial"><locus>79r</locus>2 decorated initial-word panels accompanied with a full floral border inhabited by birds, puttos and decorated with medallions containing figures and a coat of arms, in colours and gold.  
							</decoNote><decoNote type="initial"><locus>5v</locus> Decorated initial word panel, in colours and gold.
							</decoNote><decoNote type="miniature"><locus>5v</locus>Miniature, in colours and gold. 
							</decoNote><decoNote type="initial">
								Numerous initial-word panels decorated with penwork and pen-flourishing, in red and blue ink. </decoNote><decoNote type="border">Vertical bands with penwork decoration.
								
							</decoNote></decoDesc><bindingDesc><binding><p> BM in-house. Spine title: 'Compend. Leges et Institut Mosaic. Tom II (Hebrew). Brit. Mus. Bibl. Harl. 5716 Plut. XXXI P.'</p></binding></bindingDesc></physDesc><history><origin><origDate when="1475"/><origPlace>Italy, N. E. Ferrara</origPlace></origin><provenance>Acquisition: 
								Edward Harley: bought by him through Nathaniel Noel (b. 1681, d. 1753), for £20 1s (price of the two volumes, see ; ); inscription by Harley's librarian, Humfrey Wanley, 18 January 1723/4 (folio 1r). The Harley Collection, formed by Robert Harley (b. 1661, d. 1724), 1st earl of Oxford and Mortimer, politician, and Edward Harley (b. 1689, d. 1741), 2nd earl of Oxford and Mortimer, book collector and patron of the arts.
Edward Harley bequeathed the library to his widow, Henrietta Cavendish, née Holles (b. 1694, d. 1755) during her lifetime and thereafter to their daughter, Margaret Cavendish Bentinck (b. 1715, d.1785), duchess of Portland; the manuscripts were sold by the Countess and the Duchess in 1753 to the nation for £10,000 (a fraction of their contemporary value) under the Act of Parliament that also established the British Museum; the Harley manuscripts form one of the foundation collections of the British Library.</provenance></history></msDesc></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><facsimile><surface n="78v" xml:id="surface-lewis-e-206-164"><graphic height="4412px" url="master/5506_0163.tif" width="3590px"/><graphic height="190px" url="thumb/5506_0163_thumb.jpg" width="154px"/><graphic height="1800px" url="web/5506_0163_web.jpg" width="1464px"/></surface></facsimile></TEI>