<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><teiHeader><fileDesc><titleStmt><title>Description of Shibole ha-leḳeṭ and Hilkhot isur ve-heter by Zidkiyahu figlio di Abraham ha-Rofe Anav.</title><respStmt><resp>cataloger</resp><persName>Ilana Tahan</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>submitter</resp><persName>Agata Paluch</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>converted to OPenn TEI format</resp><orgName>Schoenberg Institute for Manuscript Studies</orgName></respStmt><funder>The Polonsky Foundation</funder></titleStmt><publicationStmt><publisher>The British Library</publisher><availability><licence target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">This metadata, accompanying images, and the content of
                                        London, British Library, Oriental Manuscripts Add MS 15437: Shibole ha-leḳeṭ and Hilkhot isur ve-heter by Zidkiyahu figlio di Abraham ha-Rofe Anav. are free of known
                                        copyright restrictions and in the public domain. See the
                                        Creative Commons Zero 1.0 Universal page for usage details,
                                        https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/.</licence><licence target="https://www.bl.uk/help/ethical-terms-of-use">
                                        The [British] Library respects the intellectual property
                                        rights, including moral rights, of rights holders and makes
                                        all reasonable effort to contact and consult rights owners,
                                        including, where appropriate, communities directly, or via
                                        local community organisations. Given the importance of the
                                        historical record, and the fact that that some of our
                                        digitised collections include materials that are sensitive
                                        to particular communities and groups, we ask that any use of
                                        the digitised collections is undertaken with the appropriate
                                        care. Irrespective of its copyright status, items and/or
                                        collections should not be altered or used in ways that might
                                        be derogatory to the originating individuals or communities.
                                        (Please follow the link for the complete text of the BL
                                        Ethical Terms of Use)</licence></availability></publicationStmt><notesStmt><note>Incomplete at the beginning and at the end. Three leaves cancelled after folio 148, and two after folio 234.</note><note>Latin notes on the lower half of folio 236v: 'ex Bibliotheca, non J.B. Colbert, sed Caroli Joachimi Colbert Episcopi Montispessulani, quae A.D. 1740 publica subhastationis lege fuit dividenda.'An English description of the manuscript, pasted on the paper flyleaves at the beginning of the volume, folios 1v, 2r.</note><note type="relatedResource">
								Manuscript description based on Margoliouth, G.: Catalogue of the Hebrew and Samaritan Manuscripts in the British Museum, London 1965.
							</note></notesStmt><sourceDesc><msDesc><msIdentifier><country>United Kingdom</country><settlement>London</settlement><institution>British Library</institution><repository>Oriental Manuscripts</repository><collection>Hebrew Manuscripts Digitisation
                                            Project</collection><idno type="call-number">Add MS 15437</idno><altIdentifier type="resource"><idno>http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_15437</idno></altIdentifier><altIdentifier type="bl_website"><idno>https://www.bl.uk/hebrew-manuscripts</idno></altIdentifier></msIdentifier><msContents><summary>Shibole ha-leḳeṭ and Hilkhot isur ve-heter by Zidkiyahu figlio di Abraham ha-Rofe Anav.</summary><textLang mainLang="he"/><msItem n="1r"><locus from="1r" to="236v">1r-236v</locus><title>Shibole ha-leḳeṭ שבלי הלקט</title></msItem><msItem n="237r"><locus from="237r" to="363v">237r-363v</locus><title>Hilkhot isur ve-heter הלכות איסור והיתר</title></msItem></msContents><physDesc><objectDesc><supportDesc material="parchment"><support><p>Parchment</p></support><extent>363 folios 
									
								</extent><foliation>The manuscript has two different foliations, one in the Hebrew order of folios, the other in the Latin order of folios.</foliation><collation><p>
									41 quires of mostly 10 leaves each, numbered on the first leaf, in the left-hand upper corner. 
									Wanting quires no. 1-4, the first leaf of the 5th quire and the last leaf of the 41st quire.
								</p></collation></supportDesc><layoutDesc><layout><p>Columns: 1;
                                                  ruled lines: 33;
                                                  written lines: 33; Uniform layout. Visible hard-point ruling. Hair-side and flesh-side of the folios distinguishable.Last line written outside the ruling.Catchwords at the end of the quires, partially preserved.</p></layout></layoutDesc></objectDesc><scriptDesc><scriptNote>Italian semi-cursive script of the 15th century.</scriptNote></scriptDesc><bindingDesc><binding><p> Post-1600. Brown leather, blind tooled, with Colbert's coat of arms on the upper and lower cover. Spine title: 'R. Zidkiah ben Abraham. Shebile Halleket. Hebraice. Mus. Brit. Iure Emptionis. 15,437.'</p></binding></bindingDesc></physDesc><history><origin><origDate notBefore="1400" notAfter="1499"/><origPlace>Italy</origPlace></origin><provenance>Acquisition: 
								Thomas Rodd the younger (b. 1796, d. 1849): purchased from him by the British Museum on 18 January 1845 (folio [364v]).</provenance></history></msDesc></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><facsimile><surface n="78v" xml:id="surface-lewis-e-206-164"><graphic height="4412px" url="master/5506_0163.tif" width="3590px"/><graphic height="190px" url="thumb/5506_0163_thumb.jpg" width="154px"/><graphic height="1800px" url="web/5506_0163_web.jpg" width="1464px"/></surface></facsimile></TEI>