<?altova_sps ..\Enrich_new.sps?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader rend="visible">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Hebrew Manuscripts Catalogue</title>
				<principal>Ilana Tahan</principal>
				<funder>BL</funder>
				<sponsor>The Polonsky Foundation </sponsor>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>British Library</publisher>
				<pubPlace/>
				<date calendar="Gregorian">2014-02-05</date>
				<idno>Uk</idno>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblFull>
					<titleStmt>
						<title/>
					</titleStmt>
					<publicationStmt>
						<p/>
					</publicationStmt>
				</biblFull>
				<msDesc xml:id="Uk_Or_4445" xml:lang="en" rend="meta">
					<msIdentifier rend="visible">
						<country>United Kingdom</country>
						<settlement>London</settlement>
						<institution>British Library</institution>
						<repository>Oriental Manuscripts</repository>
						<collection>Hebrew Manuscripts Digitisation Project</collection>
						<idno>Or 4445</idno>
					</msIdentifier>
					<head>Pentateuch</head>
					<msContents class="lccn.loc.gov/n79066420" rend="visible">
						<summary>Pentateuch with vowel-points and accents, masorah magna and parva, aka London Codex. </summary>
						<textLang mainLang="he">Hebrew</textLang>
						<msItem n="0" rend="visible" class="lccn.loc.gov/n79066420">
							<locus from="1v" to="186v"/>
							<title xml:lang="he">תורה</title>
							<title xml:lang="he-Latn-x-lc">Torah</title>
							<title xml:lang="en">Pentateuch</title>
							<listBibl>
								<bibl>
									<ref target="Kiryat_Sefer_61" type="number">141-145</ref>
								</bibl>
							</listBibl>
							<note>
								<p>Folios 1-28, 125, 128, and 159-186 were added in 1539/1540, while the rest of the volume can be dated to the 10th century.</p>
								<p>The upper perpendicular stroke of the letter lamed is considerably lengthened out in the first line of a page.</p>
								<p>The left side of the columns is irregular, the scribed not having used the elongated letters.</p>
								<p>Verse-divisions were originally altogether absent in this codex (whereas they are regularly employed in Codex Babylonicus Petropolitanus, which marks the difference between these two manuscripts).</p>
								<p>Parts of letter aleph are generally used to fill up the line, perhaps to show that the name of the scribe began with that letter (there is no sufficient certainty on the point).</p>
								<p>The punctuation, which seems to be contemporary with the consonantal text, is not the superlinear system used in Codex Babylonicus Petropolitanus, but the ordinary system associated with the Tiberian school.</p>
								<p>The text of this manuscript is identical with the Palestinian or Western recension on which the textus receptus is based, and differs from the Codex Babylonicus Petropolitanus, which contains many readings attributed to the Babylonian or Eastern recension.</p>
								<p>There is considerable divergency between this text and the commonly accepted masoretic recension with regard to the open and closed sections (petuḥot and setumot).</p>
								<p>The number of verses in each book and each weekly section are given at the end of the books and sections respectively; no simanim or mnemonic devices are used, and there are also some divergencies from the numbers as given in the masorah.</p>
								<p>The simanim are only marked twice, but the beginnings of the weekly sections are indicated by a later hand in the margins.</p>
								<p>Both masorah magna and parva were probably written up to a century later that the text. The later annotations seem to prove the Persian affinities of the manuscript.</p>
								<p>The masorah parva does not generally indicate קרי in the margins. The masorah magna frequently has a different way of expressing the masoretic statements than the one found in <ref target="Ginsburg_1880"/>.</p>
								<p>There are several references to masoretic  authorities, including Ben Asher (see folios 40v, 106r).</p>
								<p>On folio 40r there is a statement indicating that there once existed a whole Bible written by the same scribe and punctuated by the same punctuator.</p>
							</note>
							<filiation>The handwriting and the ink in this volume seems to be identical with &quot;Codex Babylonicus Petropolitanus&quot; which is dated <date calendar="Gregorian">916</date>, and is also similar to the &quot;Leningrad Codex&quot; (dated <date calendar="Gregorian">1008/1010</date>) and the &quot;Aleppo Codex&quot; (aka Keter
Aram Tsova, dated <date calendar="Gregorian">930</date>). </filiation>
							<colophon xml:lang="he">נשלם ב<date calendar="AM">יום ג&apos; בשבת דהוא י&quot;ז יומין לירח מרחשון דשנת אלפא ותמני מאה וחמשין וחד שנין למניין שטרות</date> אנ&quot;ס

וכתב הצעיר מכל ישראל יועץ ש[?ל?]

ודורש עזרת ה[?אל? ...]
מפחו בן [ ]

בן מ[ ].<locus n="186v"/>
							</colophon>
						</msItem>
						<msItem rend="visible">
							<locus from="1v" to="42r"/>
							<title xml:lang="en">Genesis</title>
							<note>
								<p>The first 28 leaves, belonging to the later portion, are much mutilated. The ancient part begins with chapter 39:20, on folio 29r.</p>
							</note>
						</msItem>
						<msItem rend="visible">
							<locus from="42r" to="85r"/>
							<title xml:lang="en" rend="visible">Exodus</title>
						</msItem>
						<msItem rend="visible">
							<locus from="85r" to="115r"/>
							<title xml:lang="en">Leviticus</title>
						</msItem>
						<msItem rend="visible">
							<locus from="115r" to="158v"/>
							<title xml:lang="en">Numbers</title>
						</msItem>
						<msItem rend="visible">
							<locus from="158v" to="186v"/>
							<title xml:lang="en">Deuteronomy</title>
							<note>
								<p>The ancient part ends with chapter 1:33. The rest, belonging to the later portion, is much mutilated.</p>
							</note>
						</msItem>
					</msContents>
					<physDesc rend="visible">
						<p>Vellum and paper codex; the majority of text is written in square script of probably 10th century, and the more recent paper additions with Yemenite square script come from the 16th century.</p>
						<objectDesc form="codex">
							<supportDesc material="mixed">
								<support>Parchment and paper. </support>
								<extent>186 folios <dimensions unit="mm" type="leaf">
										<height>418</height>
										<width>334</width>
									</dimensions>
									<dimensions type="written" unit="mm">
										<height>284</height>
										<width>248</width>
									</dimensions>
								</extent>
								<foliation>
									<p>186 folios (+ 2 unfoliated paper flyleaves at the beginning and at the end). </p>
								</foliation>
								<collation>
									<p>The original arrangement of quires is uncertain.</p>
									<p>Leaves have been cancelled in different parts.</p>
									<p>Many of the extant folios are irregularly joined together.</p>
									<p>Signatures are found on some of the folios, marking the beginning of quires, with Arabic letters on the upper left-hand corner and with Hebrew letters on the right-hand corner.</p>
								</collation>
								<condition>
									<p>A considerable number of leaves are mutilated.</p>
									<p>Some folios are more or less damaged (e.g. folios 122r, 122v, 123r, 123v, 124r, 124v, 126r, 126v, 127r, 127v).</p>
								</condition>
							</supportDesc>
							<layoutDesc>
								<layout columns="3" ruledLines="21" writtenLines="21">
									<p>Ruling is visible. </p>
									<p>Several lacunae.</p>
									<p>Each pericope divided into sections.</p>
									<p>The upper perpendicular stroke of the letter lamed is considerably lengthened out in the first line of a page. Parts of letter aleph are generally used to fill up the line</p>
									<p>The left side of the columns is irregular, the scribed not having used the elongated letters.</p>
								</layout>
							</layoutDesc>
						</objectDesc>
						<handDesc hands="2">
							<summary>Oriental square script of probably 10th century, with more recent paper additions with Yemenite square script of the 16th century. <name type="person" role="scribe">Nissi ben Daniel</name>, probably also the punctuator of the manuscript (see <ref target="Kiryat_Sefer_61" type="page"> 141-145</ref>): inscribed in the masoretic notes, folios 40r, 113v, 139r.</summary>
							<handNote script="Hebrew" scope="major">
								<p/>
							</handNote>
						</handDesc>
						<additions>
							<p>Folios 1r-28v, 125r-125v , 128r-128v and 159r-186v, which are paper, were added in <date calendar="Gregorian">1540</date>. </p>
							<p>An illegible owner&apos;s note in Persian (in Hebrew characters), folio 186v.</p>
						</additions>
						<bindingDesc>
							<binding>
								<p>BM/BL in-house. </p>
							</binding>
						</bindingDesc>
					</physDesc>
					<history rend="visible">
						<origin notBefore="0920" notAfter="0950">Alternative dating: <date calendar="Gregorian">820-850</date>.</origin>
						<provenance>
							<p>
								<name type="place">Egypt</name> ? or <name type="place">Palestine</name>?</p>
						</provenance>
						<acquisition>
							<p><name type="org">Mrs C. D. Sassoon &amp; Co.</name> : purchased by the British Museum on <date calendar="Gregorian">09 May 1891</date>, inscribed folio <locus n="fse002v"/>.</p>
							<date>1891-05-09</date>
						</acquisition>
					</history>
					<additional rend="visible">
						<adminInfo>
							<recordHist>
								<source>Manuscript description based on Margoliouth, G.: Catalogue of the Hebrew and Samaritan Manuscripts in the British Museum, London 1965.</source>
							</recordHist>
							<availability status="restricted">
								<p/>
							</availability>
							<note/>
						</adminInfo>
						<listBibl>
							<bibl>
								<ref target="Margoliouth_1965" type="number">64</ref>
							</bibl>
						</listBibl>
					</additional>
				</msDesc>
				<bibl/>
				<listBibl>
					<bibl/>
				</listBibl>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<classDecl>
				<taxonomy/>
			</classDecl>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc/>
		<revisionDesc status="submitted">
			<change when="2014-02-05">Agata Paluch</change>
		</revisionDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div/>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
